<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL032017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>3</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>12</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170622 10:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170622 03:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201706221500</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1000 AM CDT Thu Jun 22</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1498143600</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL DEPRESSION</systemType>
<systemName>CINDY</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>31.0</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-93.5</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>31.0N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>93.5W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>35</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>55</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>30</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>997</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.44</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>N OR 10 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>13</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>20</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>11</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 165 MI...265 KM NW OF MORGAN CITY LOUISIANA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT3 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Depression Cindy Advisory Number  12
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL032017
1000 AM CDT Thu Jun 22 2017

...CINDY WEAKENS BUT HEAVY RAINS CONTINUE...


SUMMARY OF 1000 AM CDT...1500 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...31.0N 93.5W
ABOUT 165 MI...265 KM NW OF MORGAN CITY LOUISIANA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...35 MPH...55 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...N OR 10 DEGREES AT 13 MPH...20 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...997 MB...29.44 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Tropical Storm Warning from High Island Texas to Morgan City
Louisiana has been discontinued.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

There are no coastal watches of warnings in effect.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1000 AM CDT (1500 UTC), the center of Tropical Depression Cindy
was located near latitude 31.0 North, longitude 93.5 West. The
depression is moving toward the north near 13 mph (20 km/h), and a
turn toward the north-northeast is expected later today, followed by
a turn toward the northeast on Friday.  On the forecast track, Cindy
or its remnants will move into southeastern Arkansas early Friday,
and into Tennessee later on Friday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 35 mph (55 km/h) with higher gusts.
Additional weakening is forecast and the depression is expected to
become a remnant low by Friday if not sooner.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 997 mb (29.44 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Cindy is expected to produce rain accumulations of 3 to 6
inches with isolated maximum amounts up to 8 inches over extreme
eastern Texas, Louisiana, and southern and eastern Arkansas
through Friday morning.  Additional rainfall amounts of 2 to 4
inches with isolated maximum amounts of 8 inches over southern
Mississippi, southern and central Alabama, and extreme western
Florida Panhandle are expected through Friday morning.  This may
bring storm total rainfall in excess of 15 inches in some isolated
locations. This rainfall could cause life-threatening flash flooding
in these areas.

Heavy rainfall will expand across the Tennessee and Ohio valleys
today and across the central Appalachians Friday into Saturday.
Rainfall amounts of 2 to 4 inches with isolated maximum amounts of
6 inches are expected through Friday morning.

WIND:  Gusts of tropical storm force in a few squalls are still
possible mainly to the east of the depression.

STORM SURGE:  Inundation of 1 to 3 feet above ground level is still
possible along the northern Gulf of Mexico coast in areas of strong
onshore winds.

TORNADOES:  A few tornadoes are possible through tonight from the
lower Mississippi and Tennessee Valley regions to the central Gulf
Coast.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
This is the last public advisory issued by the National Hurricane
Center on this system. Future information on this system can be
found in Public Advisories issued by the Weather Prediction Center
beginning at 4 PM CDT, under AWIPS header TCPAT3, WMO header
WTNT33 KWNH, and on the web at http://www.wpc.ncep.noaa.gov.

$$
Forecaster Avila

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
