<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>3A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170807 08:00:00 AM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170807 12:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708071200</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0800 AM EDT Mon Aug 07</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502107200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>17.3</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-84.7</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>17.3N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>84.7W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>50</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>75</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>45</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>1004</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.65</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 300 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>13</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>20</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>11</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 230 MI...370 KM E OF BELIZE CITY</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 250 MI...400 KM ESE OF CHETUMAL MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Intermediate Advisory Number 3A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
800 AM EDT Mon Aug 07 2017

...FRANKLIN GRADUALLY STRENGTHENING...


SUMMARY OF 800 AM EDT...1200 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...17.3N 84.7W
ABOUT 230 MI...370 KM E OF BELIZE CITY
ABOUT 250 MI...400 KM ESE OF CHETUMAL MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...50 MPH...75 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 300 DEGREES AT 13 MPH...20 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...1004 MB...29.65 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of Belize has changed the Tropical Storm Watch to a
Tropical Storm Warning from Belize City northward to the border of
Mexico.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Chetumal to Punta Allen

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Belize City northward to the border of Mexico
* The coast of Mexico from Chetumal to Campeche

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Campeche to Sabancuy

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area, in this case within the next 24 hours.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area, in this case within
24 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area.

Interests elsewhere around the Bay of Campeche should monitor the
progress of this system.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 800 AM EDT (1200 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin was
located near latitude 17.3 North, longitude 84.7 West. Franklin is
moving toward the west-northwest near 13 mph (20 km/h), and this
general motion is expected to continue over the next 48 hours.  On
the forecast track, the center of Franklin will pass well north of
Honduras today, then approach the east coast of the Yucatan
peninsula by late afternoon.  Franklin is then expected to move
across the Yucatan Peninsula tonight and on Tuesday.

Maximum sustained winds have increased to near 50 mph (85 km/h) with
higher gusts.  Strengthening is forecast until the center reaches
the eastern coast of the Yucatan peninsula, and Franklin could be
near hurricane strength by the time landfall occurs this evening.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 1004 mb (29.65 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Rainfall amounts of 3 to 6 inches, with isolated amounts
of around 12 inches, are possible across the Yucatan Peninsula of
Mexico and Belize through Wednesday.  These rains could produce
life-threatening flash floods.

WIND:  Hurricane conditions are possible in the Hurricane Watch
area by this evening.  Tropical Storm conditions are expected to
begin in portions of the warning area this afternoon or evening.
Tropical Storm conditions are possible in the watch area in Mexico
on Tuesday.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1100 AM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Pasch

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
