<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>9</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170808 04:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170808 09:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708082100</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0400 PM CDT Tue Aug 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502226000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>20.2</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-90.3</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>20.2N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>90.3W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>40</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>65</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>35</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>1001</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.56</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 290 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>12</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>19</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>10</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 25 MI...40 KM NNE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Advisory Number   9
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
400 PM CDT Tue Aug 08 2017

...FRANKLIN EXPECTED TO MOVE INTO THE BAY OF CAMPECHE SOON...


SUMMARY OF 400 PM CDT...2100 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...20.2N 90.3W
ABOUT 25 MI...40 KM NNE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...40 MPH...65 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 290 DEGREES AT 12 MPH...19 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...1001 MB...29.56 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Rio Lagartos to Sabancuy
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Sabancuy to Puerto de Veracruz

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 400 PM CDT (2100 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin was
located near latitude 20.2 North, longitude 90.3 West. Franklin is
moving toward the west-northwest near 12 mph (19 km/h).  A mainly
westward motion is expected over the next couple of days.  On the
forecast track, the center of Franklin will move into the Bay of
Campeche in a few hours, move westward across the Bay of Campeche
tonight and Wednesday, and be near the coast of mainland Mexico
Wednesday night or early Thursday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 40 mph (65 km/h) with higher gusts.
A strengthening trend is likely to begin when the center moves
over water, and Franklin could be near hurricane intensity at
landfall in the southwest Gulf coast of Mexico.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 1001 mb (29.56 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Franklin is expected to produce total rainfall
accumulations of 4 to 8 inches, and isolated maximum amounts of 12
inches are possible across portions of the Yucatan Peninsula of
Mexico through Wednesday.  Rainfall totals of 2 to 4 inches with
isolated maximum amounts of 8 inches are possible across northern
portions of Belize and northern portions of Guatemala.  Rainfall
totals of 4 to 8 inches with isolated maximum amounts of 15 inches
are possible across the Mexican states of Tabasco, northern
Veracruz, northern Puebla, Tlaxcala, Hidalgo, Queretaro and eastern
San Louis Potosi in eastern Mexico.  These rains may produce
life-threatening flash floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions may be occurring over portions of
the northern and western Yucatan peninsula.  Hurricane conditions
are possible within the Hurricane Watch area by Wednesday evening.
Tropical storm conditions are expected within the Tropical Storm
Warning area in mainland Mexico by Wednesday evening.  Tropical
storm conditions are possible within the tropical storm watch area
through Wednesday morning.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 2 to 4 feet above normal tide levels along the
immediate coast near and to the north of where the center
makes landfall in the Hurricane Watch area.  Near the coast, the
surge will be accompanied by large and destructive waves.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 700 PM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 1000 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Pasch

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
