<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>10A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170809 01:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170809 06:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708090600</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0100 AM CDT Wed Aug 09</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502258400</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>20.4</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-92.1</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>20.4N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>92.1W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>60</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>95</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>50</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>994</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.35</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 285 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>10</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>17</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>9</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 225 MI...360 KM NE OF COATZACOALCOS MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 280 MI...450 KM ENE OF VERACRUZ MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Intermediate Advisory Number 10A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
100 AM CDT Wed Aug 09 2017

...FRANKLIN CONTINUING TO STRENGTHEN OVER THE BAY OF CAMPECHE...


SUMMARY OF 100 AM CDT...0600 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...20.4N 92.1W
ABOUT 225 MI...360 KM NE OF COATZACOALCOS MEXICO
ABOUT 280 MI...450 KM ENE OF VERACRUZ MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...60 MPH...95 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 285 DEGREES AT 10 MPH...17 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...994 MB...29.35 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Tuxpan

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico north of Tuxpan to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico east of Puerto de Veracruz to Celestun
* The coast of Mexico north of Tuxpan to Rio Panuco

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area, in this case within 24 to 36
hours.  Preparations to protect life and property should be rushed
to completion.

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 100 AM CDT (0600 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin was
located near latitude 20.4 North, longitude 92.1 West.  Franklin is
moving toward the west-northwest near 10 mph (17 km/h).  A turn
toward the west is expected during the next several hours, with
Franklin maintaining that motion up until landfall.  On the forecast
track, the center of Franklin will move westward over the Bay of
Campeche overnight and on Wednesday and is forecast to cross the
coast of the Mexican state of Veracruz Wednesday night or early
Thursday.

Reports from an Air Force Reserve Hurricane Hunter aircraft indicate
that maximum sustained winds have increased to near 60 mph (95 km/h)
with higher gusts.  Additional strengthening is expected, and
Franklin is forecast to become a hurricane late Wednesday and
reach the coast of Mexico as a hurricane Wednesday night.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 185 miles (295 km)
from the center.  A Mexican automated weather station at Cayo
Arenas, located north of the center, recently reported a wind gust
of 45 mph (73 km/h).

The latest minimum central pressure estimated from Hurricane
Hunter aircraft data is 994 mb (29.35 inches).  A Mexican automated
weather station at Cayo Arcas, located just southwest of the center,
recently reported a pressure of 998.7 mb (29.49 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Franklin is expected to produce total rainfall
accumulations of 4 to 8 inches, and isolated maximum amounts of 12
inches are possible across portions of the Yucatan Peninsula of
Mexico through tonight.  Rainfall totals of 4 to 8 inches with
isolated maximum amounts of 15 inches are possible across the
Mexican states of Tabasco, northern Veracruz, northern Puebla,
Tlaxcala, Hidalgo, Queretaro, and eastern San Louis Potosi in
eastern Mexico.  These rains may produce life-threatening flash
floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Hurricane conditions are expected to reach the coast within
the Hurricane Warning area by Wednesday night.  Winds are expected
to first reach tropical storm strength on Wednesday, making outside
preparations difficult or dangerous.  Preparations to protect life
and property should be rushed to completion.

Tropical storm conditions are expected across portions of the
Tropical Storm Warning area along the southern shore of the
Bay of Campeche through Wednesday night. Hurricane conditions are
possible within the Hurricane Watch area Wednesday night.  Tropical
storm conditions are expected within the Tropical Storm Warning area
in eastern Mexico by Wednesday evening.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 2 to 4 feet above normal tide levels along the
immediate coast near and to the north of where the center
makes landfall in the Hurricane Warning area.  Near the coast, the
surge will be accompanied by large and destructive waves.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 400 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Beven

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
