<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>6A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170808 01:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170808 06:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708080600</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0100 AM CDT Tue Aug 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502172000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>19.1</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-88</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>19.1N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>88.0W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>60</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>95</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>50</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>996</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.41</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 295 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>14</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>22</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>12</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 45 MI...75 KM NNE OF CHETUMAL MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 170 MI...275 KM ESE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Intermediate Advisory Number 6A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
100 AM CDT Tue Aug 08 2017

...FRANKLIN MOVING FARTHER INLAND OVER THE YUCATAN PENINSULA...
...HEAVY RAINS AND FLASH FLOODING POSSIBLE ACROSS THE YUCATAN
PENINSULA AND BELIZE...


SUMMARY OF 100 AM CDT...0600 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...19.1N 88.0W
ABOUT 45 MI...75 KM NNE OF CHETUMAL MEXICO
ABOUT 170 MI...275 KM ESE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...60 MPH...95 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 295 DEGREES AT 14 MPH...22 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...996 MB...29.41 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Belize City northward to the Belize/Mexico border
* The coast of Mexico from Chetumal to Sabancuy

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Sabancuy to Puerto de Veracruz

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.  A watch is typically issued 48 hours
before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-force
winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 100 AM CDT (0600 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin was
located by the Belize City Doppler weather radar to be near latitude
19.1 North, longitude 88.0 West. Franklin is moving toward the
west-northwest near 14 mph (22 km/h).  A west-northwestward to
westward motion is expected during the next couple of days.  On the
forecast track, the center of Franklin will move across the Yucatan
peninsula through today, and emerge over the Bay of Campeche
tonight.  Franklin will then continue westward across the Bay of
Campeche on Wednesday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 60 mph (95 km/h) with higher
gusts. Weakening is expected while Franklin moves across the Yucatan
peninsula today.  Restrengthening is forecast to begin tonight and
Wednesday while Franklin moves over the Bay of Campeche.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 996 mb (29.41 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Rainfall amounts of 3 to 6 inches, with isolated amounts
of around 12 inches, are possible across the Yucatan peninsula of
Mexico and Belize through Wednesday, with the highest amounts over
the Mexican state of Quintana Roo.  These rains could produce
life-threatening flash floods.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are likely occurring over portions
of the east coast of the Yucatan peninsula and should spread
westward across the remainder of the warning area today.  Hurricane
or tropical storm conditions are possible within the hurricane watch
area by late Wednesday.  Tropical storm conditions are possible
within the tropical storm watch area tonight and Wednesday.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 2 feet above normal tide levels along the east coast of
the Yucatan peninsula early this morning.  The surge will be
accompanied by large and destructive waves. Water levels are
expected to diminish after sunrise.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 400 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Stewart/Landsea

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
