<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>7</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170808 04:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170808 09:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708080900</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0400 AM CDT Tue Aug 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502182800</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>19.3</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-88.5</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>19.3N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>88.5W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>50</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>85</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>45</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>998</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.47</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 290 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>14</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>22</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>12</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 55 MI...90 KM NNW OF CHETUMAL MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 135 MI...220 KM ESE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Advisory Number   7
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
400 AM CDT Tue Aug 08 2017

...FRANKLIN WEAKENS OVER THE INTERIOR OF THE YUCATAN PENINSULA...
...HEAVY RAINS AND FLASH FLOODING POSSIBLE ACROSS THE YUCATAN
PENINSULA AND SOUTHEASTERN MEXICO...


SUMMARY OF 400 AM CDT...0900 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...19.3N 88.5W
ABOUT 55 MI...90 KM NNW OF CHETUMAL MEXICO
ABOUT 135 MI...220 KM ESE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...50 MPH...85 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 290 DEGREES AT 14 MPH...22 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...998 MB...29.47 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Belize City northward to the Belize/Mexico border
* The coast of Mexico from Chetumal to Sabancuy

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Sabancuy to Puerto de Veracruz

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.  A watch is typically issued 48 hours
before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-force
winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 400 AM CDT (0900 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin
was located by the Belize Weather Service Doppler radar to be near
latitude 19.3 North, longitude 88.5 West. Franklin is moving toward
the west-northwest near 14 mph (22 km/h).  A west-northwestward to
westward motion is expected during the next couple of days.  On the
forecast track, the center of Franklin will continue to move across
the Yucatan peninsula through today, and emerge over the Bay of
Campeche tonight. Franklin will then move westward across the Bay of
Campeche on Wednesday.

Maximum sustained winds have decreased to near 50 mph (85 km/h) with
higher gusts. Weakening is expected while Franklin moves across the
Yucatan peninsula today.  Restrengthening is forecast to begin
tonight and Wednesday while Franklin moves over the Bay of Campeche.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
from the center. Wind gusts to 47 mph (76 km/h) in squalls have been
measured during the past couple of hours by NOAA Buoy 42056,
located more than 200 miles east-northeast of Franklin's center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 998 mb (29.47 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Rainfall amounts of 3 to 6 inches, with isolated amounts
of around 12 inches, are possible across the Yucatan Peninsula of
Mexico and Belize through Wednesday, with the highest amounts over
the Mexican state of Quintana Roo.  In addition, Franklin is
expected to bring 4 to 8 inches of rainfall with isolated amounts
up to 15 inches through Thursday to northern Veracruz, Puebla,
Tlaxcala, Hidalgo, and eastern San Louis Potosi in eastern Mexico.
These rains will be capable of producing life-threatening flash
floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are likely still occurring over
portions of the east coast of the Yucatan peninsula. These
conditions should spread westward across the remainder of the
warning area today and diminish along the east coast of the Yucatan
peninsula later this morning. Hurricane or tropical storm conditions
are possible within the hurricane watch area by late Wednesday.
Tropical storm conditions are possible within the tropical storm
watch area tonight and Wednesday.

STORM SURGE:  A storm surge will raise water levels by as much
as 1 foot above normal tide levels along the east coast of the
Yucatan peninsula early this morning.  The surge will be
accompanied by large and destructive waves. Water levels are
expected to diminish after sunrise.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 700 AM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 1000 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Stewart

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
