<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>7A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170808 07:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170808 12:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708081200</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 AM CDT Tue Aug 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502193600</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>19.5</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-89.1</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>19.5N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>89.1W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>45</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>75</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>40</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>999</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.50</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 290 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>14</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>22</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>12</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 85 MI...140 KM NW OF CHETUMAL MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 95 MI...155 KM ESE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Intermediate Advisory Number 7A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
700 AM CDT Tue Aug 08 2017

...FRANKLIN MOVING OVER THE YUCATAN PENINSULA...


SUMMARY OF 700 AM CDT...1200 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...19.5N 89.1W
ABOUT 85 MI...140 KM NW OF CHETUMAL MEXICO
ABOUT 95 MI...155 KM ESE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...45 MPH...75 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 290 DEGREES AT 14 MPH...22 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...999 MB...29.50 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of Belize has discontinued the Tropical Storm
Warning for Belize.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Chetumal to Sabancuy

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Sabancuy to Puerto de Veracruz

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.  A watch is typically issued 48 hours
before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-force
winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 AM CDT (1200 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin was
located near latitude 19.5 North, longitude 89.1 West.  Franklin is
moving toward the west-northwest near 14 mph (22 km/h).  A
west-northwestward to westward motion is expected over the next
couple of days.  On the forecast track, the center of Franklin will
continue to move across the Yucatan peninsula today, and emerge over
the Bay of Campeche this evening or tonight.  Franklin will then
move westward across the Bay of Campeche on Wednesday.

Maximum sustained winds have decreased to near 45 mph (75 km/h)
with higher gusts.  Additional weakening is expected while Franklin
moves across the Yucatan peninsula today.  Restrengthening is
forecast to begin tonight and Wednesday while Franklin moves over
the Bay of Campeche.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 999 mb (29.50 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Rainfall amounts of 3 to 6 inches, with isolated amounts
of around 12 inches, are possible across the Yucatan Peninsula of
Mexico and Belize through Wednesday, with the highest amounts over
the Mexican state of Quintana Roo.  In addition, Franklin is
expected to bring 4 to 8 inches of rainfall with isolated amounts
up to 15 inches through Thursday to northern Veracruz, Puebla,
Tlaxcala, Hidalgo, and eastern San Louis Potosi in eastern Mexico.
These rains will be capable of producing life-threatening flash
floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are likely still occurring over
portions of the east coast of the Yucatan peninsula.  These
conditions should spread westward across the remainder of the
warning area today and diminish along the east coast of the Yucatan
peninsula later this morning.  Hurricane or tropical storm
conditions are possible within the hurricane watch area by late
Wednesday.  Tropical storm conditions are possible within the
tropical storm watch area tonight and Wednesday.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Pasch

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
