<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>6</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170807 10:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170808 03:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708080300</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1000 PM CDT Mon Aug 07</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502161200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>19.1</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-87.3</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>19.1N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>87.3W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>60</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>95</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>50</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>995</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.39</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 300 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>14</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>22</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>12</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 75 MI...125 KM ENE OF CHETUMAL MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 75 MI...125 KM S OF TULUM MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Advisory Number   6
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
1000 PM CDT Mon Aug 07 2017

...FRANKLIN POISED TO MAKE LANDFALL ON THE EAST COAST OF THE
YUCATAN PENINSULA VERY SOON...
...HEAVY RAINS AND FLASH FLOODING POSSIBLE ACROSS THE YUCATAN
PENINSULA AND BELIZE...


SUMMARY OF 1000 PM CDT...0300 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...19.1N 87.3W
ABOUT 75 MI...125 KM ENE OF CHETUMAL MEXICO
ABOUT 75 MI...125 KM S OF TULUM MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...60 MPH...95 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 300 DEGREES AT 14 MPH...22 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...995 MB...29.39 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of Mexico has issued a Hurricane Watch for the coast
of mainland Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz northward to Rio Panuco.
The Tropical Storm Warning has been extended southward from
Campeche to Sabancuy, and a Tropical Storm Watch has been issued
west of Sabancuy to east of Puerto de Veracruz.  The Hurricane Watch
for the east coast of the Yucatan peninsula has been discontinued.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Belize City northward to the Belize/Mexico border
* The coast of Mexico from Chetumal to Sabancuy

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Sabancuy to Puerto de Veracruz

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.  A watch is typically issued 48 hours
before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-force
winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1000 PM CDT (0300 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin was
located near latitude 19.1 North, longitude 87.3 West.  Franklin is
moving toward the west-northwest near 14 mph (22 km/h).  A west-
northwestward to westward motion is expected during the next couple
of days.  On the forecast track, the center of Franklin will cross
the east coast of the Yucatan peninsula in the next hour or two,
traverse the Yucatan peninsula overnight and on Tuesday, and emerge
over the Bay of Campeche late Tuesday.  Franklin will then continue
westward across the Bay of Campeche on Wednesday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 60 mph (95 km/h) with higher gusts.
Weakening is expected while Franklin moves across the Yucatan
peninsula overnight and on Tuesday.  Restrengthening is forecast
Tuesday night and Wednesday while Franklin moves over the Bay of
Campeche.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 995 mb (29.39 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Rainfall amounts of 3 to 6 inches, with isolated amounts
of around 12 inches, are possible across the Yucatan peninsula of
Mexico and Belize through Wednesday, with the highest amounts over
the Mexican state of Quintana Roo.  These rains could produce
life-threatening flash floods.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are likely occurring over portions
of the east coast of the Yucatan peninsula and should spread
westward across the remainder of the warning area overnight and on
Tuesday.  Hurricane or tropical storm conditions are possible within
the hurricane watch area by late Wednesday.  Tropical storm
conditions are possible within the tropical storm watch area
Tuesday night and Wednesday.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 2 to 4 feet above normal tide levels along the immediate
coast near and to the north of where the center makes landfall.
Near the coast, the surge will be accompanied by large and
destructive waves.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 100 AM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 400 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Berg

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
