<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>8</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170808 10:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170808 03:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708081500</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1000 AM CDT Tue Aug 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502204400</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>19.6</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-89.6</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>19.6N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>89.6W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>45</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>75</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>40</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>1001</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.56</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 290 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>13</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>20</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>11</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 60 MI...100 KM ESE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Advisory Number   8
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
1000 AM CDT Tue Aug 08 2017

...FRANKLIN EXPECTED TO MOVE INTO THE BAY OF CAMPECHE LATER TODAY...


SUMMARY OF 1000 AM CDT...1500 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...19.6N 89.6W
ABOUT 60 MI...100 KM ESE OF CAMPECHE MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...45 MPH...75 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 290 DEGREES AT 13 MPH...20 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...1001 MB...29.56 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of Mexico has issued a Tropical Storm Warning for
the coast of mainland Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio
Panuco, and discontinued the Tropical Storm Warning for a portion of
the Yucatan Peninsula from east of Rio Lagartos and southward to
Chetumal.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Rio Lagartos to Sabancuy
* The coast of Mexico from Puerto de Veracruz to Rio Panuco

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Sabancuy to Puerto de Veracruz

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1000 AM CDT (1500 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin was
located near latitude 19.6 North, longitude 89.6 West. Franklin is
moving toward the west-northwest near 13 mph (20 km/h).  A
west-northwestward to westward motion is expected over the next
couple of days.  On the forecast track, the center of Franklin will
move into the Bay of Campeche later today, move westward across the
Bay of Campeche tonight and Wednesday, and be near the coast of
mainland Mexico Wednesday night or early Thursday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 45 mph (75 km/h) with higher gusts.
Some weakening is likely until the center moves back over water, and
strengthening is expected thereafter until landfall occurs in
mainland Mexico.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 1001 mb (29.56 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Franklin is expected to produce total rainfall
accumulations of 4 to 8 inches and isolated maximum amounts of 12
inches are possible across portions of the Yucatan Peninsula of
Mexico through Wednesday.  Rainfall totals of 2 to 4 inches with
isolated maximum amounts of 8 inches are possible across northern
portions of Belize and northern portions of Guatemala.  Rainfall
totals of 4 to 8 inches with isolated maximum amounts of 15 inches
are possible across the Mexican states of Tabasco, northern
Veracruz, northern Puebla, Tlaxacala, Hidalgo, Queretar and eastern
San Louis Potosi in eastern Mexico.  These rains may produce
life-threatening flash floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are likely still occurring over
portions of the northern and western Yucatan peninsula.
Hurricane conditions are possible within the Hurricane Watch area
by Wednesday evening.  Tropical storm conditions are expected
within the Tropical Storm Warning area in mainland Mexico by
Wednesday evening.  Tropical storm conditions are possible
within the tropical storm watch area today and tonight.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 2 to 4 feet above normal tide levels along the
immediate coast near and to the north of where the center
makes landfall in the Hurricane Watch area.  Near the coast, the
surge will be accompanied by large and destructive waves.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 100 PM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 400 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Pasch

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
