<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL072017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>5A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170807 07:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170808 12:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708080000</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 PM CDT Mon Aug 07</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1502150400</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>FRANKLIN</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>18.8</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-86.5</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>18.8N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>86.5W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>60</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>95</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>50</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>995</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.38</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 310 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>13</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>20</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>11</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 120 MI...195 KM E OF CHETUMAL MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 125 MI...200 KM SSE OF COZUMEL MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Franklin Intermediate Advisory Number 5A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL072017
700 PM CDT Mon Aug 07 2017

...FRANKLIN APPROACHING THE EAST COAST OF THE YUCATAN PENINSULA...


SUMMARY OF 700 PM CDT...0000 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...18.8N 86.5W
ABOUT 120 MI...195 KM E OF CHETUMAL MEXICO
ABOUT 125 MI...200 KM SSE OF COZUMEL MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...60 MPH...95 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 310 DEGREES AT 13 MPH...20 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...995 MB...29.38 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Chetumal to Punta Allen

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Belize City northward to the border of Mexico
* The coast of Mexico from Chetumal to Campeche

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Mexico from Campeche to Sabancuy

Interests elsewhere around the Bay of Campeche should monitor the
progress of this system.  A Hurricane Watch may be required for a
portion of the southwestern Gulf coast of Mexico this evening.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 PM CDT (0000 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Franklin was
located near latitude 18.8 North, longitude 86.5 West.  Franklin is
moving toward the northwest near 13 mph (20 km/h), and a
west-northwestward to westward motion is expected over the next 48
hours.  On the forecast track, the center will continue to approach
the east coast of the Yucatan peninsula this evening and make
landfall overnight.  Franklin is then expected to move across the
Yucatan peninsula on Tuesday, and into the Bay of Campeche Tuesday
evening or Tuesday night.

Data from an Air Force Reserve Hurricane Hunter aircraft indicate
that maximum sustained winds remain near 60 mph (95 km/h) with
higher gusts.  Some strengthening is still possible before the
center reaches the Yucatan peninsula, and Franklin could be near
hurricane intensity at landfall on the east coast of the Yucatan
peninsula.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
from the center.

The minimum central pressure based on aircraft reconnaissance data
is 995 mb (29.38 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Rainfall amounts of 3 to 6 inches, with isolated amounts
of around 12 inches, are possible across the Yucatan peninsula of
Mexico and Belize through Wednesday, with the highest amounts over
the Mexican state of Quintana Roo.  These rains could produce
life-threatening flash floods.

WIND:  Hurricane conditions are possible in the Hurricane Watch
area tonight.  Tropical storm conditions are expected to
begin in portions of the warning area over the next few hours.
Tropical storm conditions are possible in the watch area in Mexico
on Tuesday.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 2 to 4 feet above normal tide levels along the immediate
coast near and to the north of where the center makes landfall.
Near the coast, the surge will be accompanied by large and
destructive waves.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Berg

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
