<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL092017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>36A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170829 07:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170829 12:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708291200</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 AM CDT Tue Aug 29</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504008000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>HARVEY</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>28.2</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-94.6</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>28.2N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>94.6W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>45</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>75</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>40</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>997</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.44</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>ENE OR 60 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>3</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>6</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>3</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT  90 MI...145 KM ESE OF PORT OCONNOR TEXAS</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 145 MI...235 KM SSW OF PORT ARTHUR TEXAS</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Harvey Intermediate Advisory Number 36A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL092017
700 AM CDT Tue Aug 29 2017

...CONTINUED HEAVY RAINFALL TODAY IS EXPECTED TO WORSEN THE
FLOOD SITUATION IN SOUTHEASTERN TEXAS AND SOUTHWESTERN LOUISIANA...
...DO NOT ATTEMPT TO TRAVEL IN THE AFFECTED AREAS IF YOU ARE IN
A SAFE PLACE, AND DO NOT DRIVE INTO FLOODED ROADWAYS...


SUMMARY OF 700 AM CDT...1200 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...28.2N 94.6W
ABOUT  90 MI...145 KM ESE OF PORT OCONNOR TEXAS
ABOUT 145 MI...235 KM SSW OF PORT ARTHUR TEXAS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...45 MPH...75 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...ENE OR 60 DEGREES AT 3 MPH...6 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...997 MB...29.44 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Mesquite Bay to Intracoastal City

A Storm Surge Watch is in effect for...
* Port Bolivar to Morgan City

Catastrophic and life-threatening flooding continues in southeastern
Texas and portions of southwestern Louisiana.  Please see warnings
and other products issued by your local National Weather Service
office for additional information on this life-threatening
situation.

A Storm Surge Watch means there is a possibility of life-
threatening inundation, from rising water moving inland from the
coastline, in the indicated locations during the next 48 hours.
For a depiction of areas at risk, please see the National Weather
Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic, available at
hurricanes.gov.

Interests elsewhere along the middle and upper Texas coast and in
southern Louisiana should continue to monitor the progress of
Harvey.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 AM CDT (1200 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Harvey was
estimated near latitude 28.2 North, longitude 94.6 West. Harvey is
moving toward the east-northeast near 3 mph (6 km/h), and this
motion is expected to continue through this morning.  A turn toward
the northeast is expected later today and tonight, followed by a
turn toward the north-northeast on Wednesday.  On the forecast
track, the center of Harvey is expected to be just offshore of the
middle and upper coasts of Texas through tonight, then move inland
over the northwestern Gulf coast on Wednesday.

Maximum sustained winds remain near 45 mph (75 km/h) with higher
gusts. Little change in strength is forecast during the next 48
hours.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 175 miles (280 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 997 mb (29.44 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Harvey is expected to produce additional rainfall
accumulations of 7 to 13 inches through Friday over parts of the
upper Texas coast into southwestern Louisiana.  Isolated storm
totals may reach 50 inches over the upper Texas coast, including the
Houston/Galveston metropolitan area.  These rains are currently
producing catastrophic and life-threatening flooding over large
portions of southeastern Texas and southwestern Louisiana.  DO NOT
ATTEMPT TO TRAVEL IN THE AFFECTED AREA IF YOU ARE IN A SAFE PLACE.
DO NOT DRIVE INTO FLOODED ROADWAYS.  Please see warnings and
products issued by your local National Weather Service office for
additional information on this life-threatening situation.

Elsewhere, Harvey is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
5 to 15 inches farther east across south-central Louisiana.
Rainfall amounts of 5 to 10 inches are expected in southeast
Louisiana and coastal Mississippi and Alabama.

A list of rainfall observations compiled by the NOAA Weather
Prediction Center can be found at:
www.wpc.ncep.noaa.gov/discussions/nfdscc1.html

STORM SURGE:  The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the
tide will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by
rising waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is
expected to reach the following heights above ground if the peak
surge occurs at the time of high tide...

Mesquite Bay to Morgan City including Galveston Bay...1 to 3 ft

The deepest water will occur along the immediate coast near the
area of onshore winds.  Surge-related flooding depends on the
relative timing of the surge and the tidal cycle, and can vary
greatly over short distances.  For information specific to your
area, please see products issued by your local National Weather
Service forecast office.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are occurring over portions of
the warning area along the coast.  Tropical storm conditions are
likely to persist within the warning area during the next couple of
days.

SURF:  Swells generated by Harvey are affecting the coasts of Texas
and Louisiana.  These swells are likely to cause life-threatening
surf and rip current conditions. Please consult products from your
local weather office.

TORNADOES:  A few tornadoes are possible through tonight from
extreme southeast Texas across southern Louisiana, southern
Mississippi and extreme southwestern Alabama.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Avila

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
