<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL092017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>42</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170830 04:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170830 09:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708302100</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0400 PM CDT Wed Aug 30</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504126800</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>HARVEY</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>30.8</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-93.1</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>30.8N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>93.1W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>40</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>65</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>35</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>998</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.47</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNE OR 20 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>8</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>13</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>7</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM N OF LAKE CHARLES LOUISIANA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM SW OF ALEXANDRIA LOUISIANA</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Harvey Advisory Number  42
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL092017
400 PM CDT Wed Aug 30 2017

...HARVEY STILL PRODUCING TROPICAL-STORM-FORCE WINDS NEAR THE
LOUISIANA COAST...
...FLOODING RAINS CONTINUING OVER EXTREME EASTERN TEXAS AND
WESTERN LOUISIANA...


SUMMARY OF 400 PM CDT...2100 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...30.8N 93.1W
ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM N OF LAKE CHARLES LOUISIANA
ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM SW OF ALEXANDRIA LOUISIANA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...40 MPH...65 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNE OR 20 DEGREES AT 8 MPH...13 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...998 MB...29.47 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Storm Surge Watch and Warning are discontinued for the coasts
of Texas and Louisiana.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Sabine Pass Texas to Grand Isle Louisiana

Catastrophic and life-threatening flooding continues in southeastern
Texas and portions of southwestern Louisiana.  Please see warnings
and other products issued by your local National Weather Service
office for additional information on this life-threatening
situation.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 400 PM CDT (2100 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Harvey was
located near latitude 30.8 North, longitude 93.1 West. Harvey is
moving erratically toward the north-northeast near 8 mph (13 km/h)
and this motion is expected to continue tonight.  A turn toward the
northeast is expected Thursday or Thursday night.  On the forecast
track, the center of Harvey should move through southwestern and
central Louisiana tonight, then move through northeastern Louisiana
and northwestern Mississippi Thursday and Thursday night.

Maximum sustained winds are near 40 mph (65 km/h) with higher gusts.
Weakening is forecast during the next 48 hours as Harvey moves
farther inland, and the cyclone is expected to weaken to a tropical
depression tonight.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles (220 km)
mainly over water to the southeast of the center.  An automated
station near Lacassine, Louisiana recently reported a wind gust of
44 mph (71 km/h).

The estimated minimum central pressure based on surface observations
is 998 mb (29.47 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Harvey is expected to produce additional rainfall
accumulations of 4 to 8 inches from southwestern Louisiana and the
adjacent border of eastern Texas northeastward into western
Tennessee and Kentucky through Friday with isolated amounts up to 12
inches.  The threat of heavy rains has ended in the Houston/
Galveston area. However catastrophic and life threatening flooding
will continue in and around Houston, Beaumont/Port Arthur, eastward
into southwest Louisiana for the rest of the week.  The expected
heavy rains spreading northeastward from Louisiana into western
Kentucky may also lead to flash flooding and increased river and
small stream flooding.  DO NOT ATTEMPT TO TRAVEL IN THE AFFECTED
AREA IF YOU ARE IN A SAFE PLACE. DO NOT DRIVE INTO FLOODED
ROADWAYS.  Please see warnings and products issued by your local
National Weather Service office for additional information on this
life-threatening situation.

Elsewhere, the outer bands of Harvey are expected to produce
additional rainfall amounts of 3 to 6 inches over portions of the
central and eastern Gulf States and 2 to 4 inches farther north into
parts of the Tennessee Valley, Ohio Valley and southern Mid Atlantic
through Saturday.  These rains may lead to flooding concerns across
these areas.

A list of preliminary rainfall observations compiled by the NOAA
Weather Prediction Center can be found at:
www.wpc.ncep.noaa.gov/discussions/nfdscc1.html

STORM SURGE:  The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the
tide will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by
rising waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is
expected to reach the following heights above ground if the peak
surge occurs at the time of high tide...

San Luis Pass to Grand Isle...1 to 2 ft

The deepest water will occur along the immediate coast near the
area of onshore winds. Surge-related flooding depends on the
relative timing of the surge and the tidal cycle, and can vary
greatly over short distances. For information specific to your
area, please see products issued by your local National Weather
Service forecast office.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are occurring over portions of
the warning area along the coast and are likely to persist through
this evening.  Gusts to tropical-storm-force are possible over
other portions of southern Louisiana through this evening.

SURF:  Swells generated by Harvey are still affecting the coast of
Louisiana, but are expected to subside late tonight and Thursday.
These swells are likely to cause life-threatening surf and rip
current conditions. Please consult products from your local weather
office.

TORNADOES:  A few tornadoes are possible through this evening across
parts of Louisiana, Mississippi, western Alabama, and southeast
Arkansas. Additional tornadoes are possible on Thursday afternoon
and evening across northern portions of Mississippi, Alabama, and
Georgia into parts of Tennessee.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 700 PM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 1000 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Beven

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
