<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL092017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>24A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170826 07:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170826 12:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708261200</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 AM CDT Sat Aug 26</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1503748800</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>HARVEY</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>28.7</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-97.2</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>28.7N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>97.2W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>80</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>130</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>70</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>975</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.79</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNW OR 340 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>6</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>9</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>5</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 20 MI...30 KM WSW OF VICTORIA TEXAS</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 95 MI...150 KM SE OF SAN ANTONIO TEXAS</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Harvey Intermediate Advisory Number 24A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL092017
700 AM CDT Sat Aug 26 2017

...HARVEY MOVING SLOWLY OVER TEXAS PRODUCING TORRENTIAL RAINS...
...CATASTROPHIC FLOODING EXPECTED OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS...


SUMMARY OF 700 AM CDT...1200 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...28.7N 97.2W
ABOUT 20 MI...30 KM WSW OF VICTORIA TEXAS
ABOUT 95 MI...150 KM SE OF SAN ANTONIO TEXAS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...80 MPH...130 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNW OR 340 DEGREES AT 6 MPH...9 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...975 MB...28.79 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for...
* Baffin Bay to High Island Texas

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Baffin Bay to Port O'Connor Texas

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* North of Port O'Connor to High Island Texas

A Storm Surge Warning means there is a danger of life-threatening
inundation from rising water moving inland from the coastline in the
indicated locations. For a depiction of areas at risk, please see
the National Weather Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic,
available at hurricanes.gov.  This is a life-threatening situation.

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning.

Interests in southwestern Louisiana should continue to monitor the
progress of this system.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 AM CDT (1200 UTC), the eye of Hurricane Harvey was located by
NOAA Doppler radar near latitude 28.7 North, longitude 97.2 West.
Harvey is moving toward the north-northwest near 6 mph (9 km/h).
Harvey is expected to slow down through the day and meander over
southeastern Texas through the middle of next week.

Doppler radar data indicate that maximum sustained winds have
decreased to near 80 mph (130 km/h) with higher gusts. These winds
are confined to a small area near the eye of the hurricane.
Additional weakening is forecast, and Harvey is likely to become a
tropical storm later today.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 35 miles (55 km) from
the center, and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140
miles (220 km).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 975 mb (28.79 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Harvey is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
15 to 30 inches and isolated maximum amounts of 40 inches over the
middle and upper Texas coast through next Wednesday. During the same
time period Harvey is expected to produce total rain accumulations
of 5 to 15 inches in far south Texas, the Texas Hill Country
and southwest and central Louisiana. Rainfall of this magnitude
will cause catastrophic and life-threatening flooding.  A list of
rainfall observations compiled by the NOAA Weather Prediction Center
can be found at: www.wpc.ncep.noaa.gov/discussions/nfdscc1.html

STORM SURGE:  The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the
tide will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by
rising waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is
expected to reach the following heights above ground if the peak
surge occurs at the time of high tide...

Port Aransas to Port O'Connor...6 to 12 ft
Port O'Connor to Sargent...6 to 9 ft
Sargent to Jamaica Beach...4 to 6 ft
Baffin Bay to Port Aransas...3 to 6 ft
Jamaica Beach to High Island...2 to 4 ft
Mouth of the Rio Grande to Port Mansfield...1 to 3 ft
High Island to Morgan City...1 to 3 ft

The deepest water will occur along the immediate coast near the
area of onshore winds, where the surge will be accompanied by large
and destructive waves.  Surge-related flooding depends on the
relative timing of the surge and the tidal cycle, and can vary
greatly over short distances.  For information specific to your
area, please see products issued by your local National Weather
Service forecast office.

WIND:  Hurricane conditions are occuring inland from the coast
within Harvey's eyewall, and hurricane-force winds, especially in
gusts, are still possible near the middle Texas coast for the next
several hours.  Tropical storm conditions are occurring in other
portions of the hurricane and tropical storm warning areas.
Tropical storm conditions are likely to persist along portions of
the coast through at least Sunday.

SURF:  Swells generated by Harvey are affecting the Texas,
Louisiana, and northeast Mexico coasts.  These swells are likely to
cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions. Please
consult products from your local weather office.

TORNADOES:  Tornadoes are possible today and tonight near the middle
and upper Texas coast into far southwest Louisiana.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Avila

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
