<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL092017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>39</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170829 10:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170830 03:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708300300</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1000 PM CDT Tue Aug 29</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504062000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>HARVEY</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>29.0</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-93.6</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>29.0N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>93.6W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>50</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>85</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>45</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>994</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.36</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NE OR 35 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>6</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>9</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>5</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 60 MI...95 KM SSW OF CAMERON LOUISIANA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 65 MI...105 KM SSE OF PORT ARTHUR TEXAS</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Harvey Advisory Number  39
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL092017
1000 PM CDT Tue Aug 29 2017

...HARVEY STILL PRODUCING HEAVY RAINS OVER FAR EAST TEXAS AND
SOUTHWESTERN LOUISIANA...


SUMMARY OF 1000 PM CDT...0300 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...29.0N 93.6W
ABOUT 60 MI...95 KM SSW OF CAMERON LOUISIANA
ABOUT 65 MI...105 KM SSE OF PORT ARTHUR TEXAS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...50 MPH...85 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NE OR 35 DEGREES AT 6 MPH...9 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...994 MB...29.36 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Tropical Storm Warning along the coast of Louisiana has been
extended eastward to Grand Isle.

The Tropical Storm Warning along the coast of Texas has been
discontinued to the south of Freeport.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for...
* Holly Beach to Morgan City

A Storm Surge Watch is in effect for...
* Port Bolivar to west of Holly Beach

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* North of Freeport Texas to Grand Isle Louisiana

Catastrophic and life-threatening flooding continues in southeastern
Texas and portions of southwestern Louisiana.  Please see warnings
and other products issued by your local National Weather Service
office for additional information on this life-threatening
situation.

A Storm Surge Warning means there is a danger of life-threatening
inundation, from rising water moving inland from the coastline,
during the next 12 to 24 hours in the indicated locations.  For a
depiction of areas at risk, please see the National Weather
Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic, available at
hurricanes.gov.  This is a life-threatening situation.  Persons
located within these areas should take all necessary actions to
protect life and property from rising water and the potential for
other dangerous conditions.  Promptly follow evacuation and other
instructions from local officials.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1000 PM CDT (0300 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Harvey was
located near latitude 29.0 North, longitude 93.6 West. Harvey is
moving toward the northeast near 6 mph (9 km/h). A north-
northeastward motion is expected later tonight and this general
motion should continue through Wednesday night.  On the forecast
track, the center of Harvey is expected to move inland over the
northwestern Gulf Coast within the tropical storm warning area early
Wednesday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 50 mph (85 km/h) with higher gusts.
No significant change in strength is anticipated before the center
crosses the coast, but gradual weakening should begin thereafter.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 160 miles (260 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 994 mb (29.36 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Harvey is expected to produce additional rainfall
accumulations of 6 to 12 inches to the north and east of Houston
from far east Texas into southwestern Louisiana.  Isolated storm
totals will reach 50 inches over the upper Texas coast, including
the Houston/Galveston metropolitan area.  These rains are currently
producing catastrophic and life-threatening flooding over large
portions of southeastern Texas and southwestern Louisiana.  DO NOT
ATTEMPT TO TRAVEL IN THE AFFECTED AREA IF YOU ARE IN A SAFE PLACE.
DO NOT DRIVE INTO FLOODED ROADWAYS.  Please see warnings and
products issued by your local National Weather Service office for
additional information on this life-threatening situation.

Elsewhere, Harvey is expected to produce total rainfall amounts of 5
to 10 inches across portions of southern Louisiana into coastal
Mississippi and Alabama. Rainfall associated with Harvey will spread
north by mid to late week, with rainfall amounts of 4 to 8 inches
spreading into portions of Arkansas and the Tennessee Valley.

A preliminary report from a rain gauge has broken the Texas tropical
cyclone rainfall record.  The Cedar Bayou gauge, east of Highlands,
Texas, has reported 51.88 inches of rain as of 3 PM CDT.  This total
is higher than the previous record of 48 inches set during tropical
cyclone Amelia of 1978 at Medina, Texas.

A list of rainfall observations compiled by the NOAA Weather
Prediction Center can be found at:
www.wpc.ncep.noaa.gov/discussions/nfdscc1.html

STORM SURGE:  The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the
tide will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by
rising waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is
expected to reach the following heights above ground if the peak
surge occurs at the time of high tide...

Holly Beach to Morgan City...2 to 4 ft
San Luis Pass to west of Holly Beach including Galveston Bay...1 to
3 ft
Morgan City to Grand Isle...1 to 2 ft

The deepest water will occur along the immediate coast near the
area of onshore winds. Surge-related flooding depends on the
relative timing of the surge and the tidal cycle, and can vary
greatly over short distances. For information specific to your
area, please see products issued by your local National Weather
Service forecast office.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are occurring over portions of
the warning area along the coast and are likely to persist through
Wednesday.

SURF:  Swells generated by Harvey are still affecting the coasts of
Texas and Louisiana.  These swells are likely to cause
life-threatening surf and rip current conditions. Please consult
products from your local weather office.

TORNADOES: A few tornadoes are possible through Wednesday across
parts of Louisiana, Mississippi, southern Alabama, and southeast
Arkansas.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 100 AM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 400 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Brown

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
