<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL122017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>12</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170908 05:00:00 AM AST</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170908 09:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709080900</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0500 AM AST Fri Sep 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504861200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>JOSE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>16.0</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-55.3</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>16.0N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>55.3W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>125</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>200</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>110</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>957</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.25</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 3</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 285 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>16</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>26</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>14</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 535 MI...865 KM ESE OF THE NORTHERN LEEWARD ISLANDS</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Jose Advisory Number  12
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL122017
500 AM AST Fri Sep 08 2017

...JOSE A LITTLE STRONGER...


SUMMARY OF 500 AM AST...0900 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...16.0N 55.3W
ABOUT 535 MI...865 KM ESE OF THE NORTHERN LEEWARD ISLANDS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...125 MPH...200 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 285 DEGREES AT 16 MPH...26 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...957 MB...28.25 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of France has issued a Hurricane Watch for the
island of St. Barthelemy.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* Antigua, Barbuda, and Anguilla
* St Maarten
* St. Martin
* St. Barthelemy

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Antigua, Barbuda, and Anguilla

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* Montserrat, St Kitts, and Nevis
* Saba and St. Eustatius

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.  A watch is typically issued 48 hours
before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-force
winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 500 AM AST (0900 UTC), the eye of Hurricane Jose was located
near latitude 16.0 North, longitude 55.3 West. Jose is moving toward
the west-northwest near 16 mph (26 km/h).  A slower west-
northwestward motion is expected during the next couple of days. On
the forecast track, Jose is expected to be near the northern Leeward
Islands on Saturday.

Maximum sustained winds have increased to near 125 mph (200 km/h)
with higher gusts.  Jose is a category 3 hurricane on the Saffir-
Simpson Hurricane Wind Scale.  Some slight strengthening is
possible later today or tonight.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 35 miles (55 km) from the
center and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 115 miles
(185 km).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 957 mb (28.25 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Hurricane conditions are possible within the hurricane watch
area on Saturday, and tropical storm conditions are expected
within the tropical storm warning areas by Saturday morning.
Tropical storm conditions are possible in the tropical storm watch
areas by Saturday morning.

RAINFALL:  Jose is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
2 to 6 inches in the Leeward Islands from Dominica to Anguilla.
Isolated maximum amounts of 10 inches are possible in the northern
Leeward Islands from Antigua and Barbuda to Anguilla. This rainfall
will maintain any ongoing flooding and may cause additional life-
threatening flooding.

SURF:  Swells generated by Jose are expected to affect portions of
the Leeward Islands by later today.  These swells are likely to
cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions.  Please
consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 800 AM AST.
Next complete advisory at 1100 AM AST.

$$
Forecaster Roberts

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
