<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL122017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>57</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170919 11:00:00 AM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170919 03:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709191500</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1100 AM EDT Tue Sep 19</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1505833200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>JOSE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>36.5</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-71.7</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>36.5N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>71.7W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>75</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>120</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>65</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>976</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.82</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>N OR 355 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>7</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>11</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>6</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 230 MI...370 KM ENE OF CAPE HATTERAS NORTH CAROLINA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 335 MI...545 KM SSW OF NANTUCKET MASSACHUSETTS</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Jose Advisory Number  57
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL122017
1100 AM EDT Tue Sep 19 2017

...JOSE MAINTAINING STATUS AS A CATEGORY 1 HURRICANE...
...DANGEROUS SURF AND RIP CURRENTS EXPECTED TO CONTINUE ALONG
THE EAST COAST OF THE UNITED STATES FOR SEVERAL MORE DAYS...


SUMMARY OF 1100 AM EDT...1500 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...36.5N 71.7W
ABOUT 230 MI...370 KM ENE OF CAPE HATTERAS NORTH CAROLINA
ABOUT 335 MI...545 KM SSW OF NANTUCKET MASSACHUSETTS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...75 MPH...120 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...N OR 355 DEGREES AT 7 MPH...11 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...976 MB...28.82 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Tropical Storm Watch has been discontinued from New Haven to
Watch Hill.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Watch Hill to Hull
* Block Island
* Martha's Vineyard
* Nantucket

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Long Island from Fire Island Inlet to Port Jefferson

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, in this case within the next 24 to
36 hours.

Interests elsewhere along the U.S. east coast from North Carolina
northward to New England should monitor the progress of Jose.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1100 AM EDT (1500 UTC), the center of Hurricane Jose was located
by an an Air Force Reserve Hurricane Hunter aircraft near latitude
36.5 North, longitude 71.7 West. Jose is moving toward the north
near 7 mph (11 km/h). This general motion is expected to continue
through today with a turn to the northeast anticipated tonight.  On
the forecast track, the center of Jose is forecast to pass well
offshore of the Delmarva peninsula later today, pass well to the
east of the New Jersey coast on Wednesday, and pass offshore of
southeastern Massachusetts by Thursday.

Maximum sustained winds remain near 75 mph (120 km/h) with higher
gusts. Little change in strength is expected today, but Jose should
begin to gradually weaken on Wednesday.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 60 miles (95 km) from the
center and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 310 miles
(500 km).  NOAA Buoy 44014, located east of the Virginia-North
Carolina border or about 160 miles west of the center of Jose,
recently reported a sustained wind of 40 mph (65 km/h).

The minimum central pressure recently reported by the reconnaissance
aircraft was 976 mb (28.82 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected to begin in the
warning area early Wednesday.  Tropical storm conditions are
possible in the watch area beginning tonight.

SURF:  Swells generated by Jose are affecting Bermuda, the Bahamas,
and much of the U.S. east coast.  These swells are likely to cause
dangerous surf and rip current conditions for the next several
days in these areas.  For more information, please consult products
from your local weather office.

RAINFALL:  Jose is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
1 to 3 inches over eastern Long Island, southeast Connecticut,
southern Rhode Island, and southeast Massachusetts. Rainfall
amounts of 3 to 5 inches are expected for Martha's Vineyard,
Nantucket and Cape Cod through Wednesday.  This rainfall could cause
isolated flooding.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 200 PM EDT.
Next complete advisory at 500 PM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Stewart

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
