<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL122017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>17</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170909 11:00:00 AM AST</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170909 03:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709091500</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1100 AM AST Sat Sep 09</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504969200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>JOSE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>18.3</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-61.3</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>18.3N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>61.3W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>145</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>230</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>125</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>945</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>27.91</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 4</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 305 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>13</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>20</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>11</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 120 MI...190 KM E OF THE NORTHERN LEEWARD ISLANDS</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Jose Advisory Number  17
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL122017
Issued by the NWS Weather Prediction Center College Park MD
1100 AM AST Sat Sep 09 2017

...JOSE REMAINS A DANGEROUS CATEGORY FOUR HURRICANE...


SUMMARY OF 1100 AM AST...1500 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...18.3N 61.3W
ABOUT 120 MI...190 KM E OF THE NORTHERN LEEWARD ISLANDS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...145 MPH...230 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 305 DEGREES AT 13 MPH...20 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...945 MB...27.91 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Tropical Storm Watch for St. Thomas and St. John in the U.S.
Virgin Island has been discontinued.

The government of Antigua has discontinued the Tropical Storm
Watch for Antigua and the British Virgin Islands.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Sint Maarten
* St. Martin
* St. Barthelemy

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Barbuda and Anguilla
* Saba and St. Eustatius

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area, in this case within 24 hours.
Preparations to protect life and property should be rushed to
completion.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

For storm information specific to your area outside the United
States, please monitor products issued by your national
meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1100 AM AST (1500 UTC), the center of Hurricane Jose was located
near latitude 18.3 North, longitude 61.3 West. Jose is moving toward
the northwest near 13 mph (20 km/h).  A continued northwest motion
is expected during the next couple of days.  On the forecast track,
the core of Jose will pass just north of the northern Leeward
Islands later today.

Maximum sustained winds are near 145 mph (230 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Jose is a category 4 hurricane on the Saffir-Simpson
Hurricane Wind Scale.  Gradual weakening is expected to occur over
the next couple of days.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 35 miles (55 km) from the
center and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 140 miles
(220 km).

The latest minimum central pressure reported by an Air Force
Reserve reconnaissance aircraft is 945 mb (27.91 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Hurricane conditions are expected within the hurricane
warning area today. Tropical storm conditions are expected within
the tropical storm warning areas through this evening.

RAINFALL:  Jose is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
2 to 4 inches in the portions of Northern Leeward Islands, with
with isolated maximum amounts of 6 inches. This rainfall will
maintain any ongoing flooding and may cause additional
life-threatening flooding.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
1 to 3 feet above normal tide levels along the immediate coast in
the hurricane warning and tropical storm warning areas.  Near the
coast, the surge will be accompanied by large and destructive waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Jose are affecting portions of the
Leeward Islands.  These swells are expected to continue for a couple
of days, and could cause life-threatening surf and rip current
conditions.  Please consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 200 PM AST.
Next complete advisory at 500 PM AST.

$$
Forecaster Brown/Cohen

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
