<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL122017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>2</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>58A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170919 08:00:00 PM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170920 12:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709200000</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0800 PM EDT Tue Sep 19</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1505865600</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>JOSE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>37.5</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-71.2</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>37.5N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>71.2W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>75</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>120</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>65</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>973</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.73</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNE OR 25 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>8</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>13</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>7</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 265 MI...460 KM SSW OF NANTUCKET MASSACHUSETTS</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT2 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Jose Intermediate Advisory Number 58A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL122017
800 PM EDT Tue Sep 19 2017

...HURRICANE JOSE WILL CONTINUE TO PRODUCE DANGEROUS SURF AND RIP
CURRENTS ALONG THE U.S. EAST COAST FOR SEVERAL MORE DAYS...


SUMMARY OF 800 PM EDT...0000 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...37.5N 71.2W
ABOUT 265 MI...460 KM SSW OF NANTUCKET MASSACHUSETTS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...75 MPH...120 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNE OR 25 DEGREES AT 8 MPH...13 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...973 MB...28.73 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Woods Hole to Sagamore Beach, including Cape Cod
* Block Island
* Martha's Vineyard
* Nantucket

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* The coast of Long Island from Fire Island Inlet to Port Jefferson

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area, in this case within the
next 24 to 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, in this case within the next 24
hours.

Interests elsewhere along the U.S. east coast from Virginia
northward to New England should monitor the progress of Jose.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 800 PM EDT (0000 UTC), the center of Hurricane Jose was located
by an Air Force reconnaissance plane near latitude 37.5 North,
longitude 71.2 West. Jose is moving toward the north-northeast near
8 mph (13 km/h), and this general motion is expected to continue
tonight. A turn to the northeast is forecast to occur by Wednesday
morning. On the forecast track, the center of Jose is expected to
pass well offshore of the Delmarva peninsula later tonight, pass
well to the east of the New Jersey coast on Wednesday, and pass
offshore of southeastern Massachusetts by Thursday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 75 mph (120 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Jose should begin to gradually weaken on Wednesday.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 60 miles (95 km) from
the center and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 310
miles (500 km).

The minimum central pressure recently reported by an Air Force plane
was 973 mb (28.73 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected to begin in the
warning area early Wednesday.  Tropical storm conditions are
possible in the watch area beginning later tonight.

SURF:  Swells generated by Jose are affecting Bermuda, the Bahamas,
and much of the U.S. east coast.  These swells are likely to cause
dangerous surf and rip current conditions for the next several
days in these areas.  For more information, please consult products
from your local weather office.

RAINFALL:  Jose is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
1 to 3 inches over eastern Long Island, southeast Connecticut,
southern Rhode Island, and southeast Massachusetts. Rainfall
amounts of 3 to 5 inches are expected for Martha's Vineyard,
Nantucket and Cape Cod through Wednesday. This rainfall could cause
isolated flooding.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1100 PM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Avila

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
