<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL132017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>3</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>7</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170907 04:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170907 09:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709070900</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0400 AM CDT Thu Sep 07</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504774800</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>KATIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>21.5</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-94.5</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>21.5N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>94.5W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>80</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>130</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>70</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>989</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.21</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>STATIONARY</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>0</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>0</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>0</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 225 MI...360 KM ESE OF TAMPICO MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 195 MI...310 KM NE OF VERACRUZ MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT3 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Katia Advisory Number   7
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL132017
400 AM CDT Thu Sep 07 2017

...HURRICANE WARNING ISSUED FOR KATIA IN THE STATE OF VERACRUZ...


SUMMARY OF 400 AM CDT...0900 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...21.5N 94.5W
ABOUT 225 MI...360 KM ESE OF TAMPICO MEXICO
ABOUT 195 MI...310 KM NE OF VERACRUZ MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...80 MPH...130 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...STATIONARY
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...989 MB...29.21 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of Mexico has issued a Hurricane Warning for the
coast of Mexico from Cabo Rojo to Laguna Verde.  The government of
Mexico has also issued a Tropical Storm Warning from north of Cabo
Rojo to Rio Panuco and from south of Laguna Verde to Puerto
Veracruz.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Cabo Rojo to Laguna Verde

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* North of Cabo Rojo to Rio Panuco
* South of Laguna Verde to Puerto Veracruz.

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area.  A warning is typically issued
36 hours before the anticipated first occurrence of
tropical-storm-force winds, conditions that make outside
preparations difficult or dangerous.  Preparations to protect life
and property should be rushed to completion.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 400 AM CDT (0900 UTC), the center of Hurricane Katia was located
near latitude 21.5 North, longitude 94.5 West. Katia is stationary
and little overall motion is anticipated through late today, but
then the hurricane is forecast to turn southwestward and approach
the coast within the watch area late Friday or early Saturday.

Maximum sustained winds remain near 80 mph (130 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Some strengthening is forecast during the next 48 hours and
Katia could be near major hurricane strength at landfall.

Katia is a small tropical cyclone. Hurricane-force winds extend
outward up to 10 miles (20 km) from the center and tropical-storm-
force winds extend outward up to 45 miles (75 km).

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 10 miles (20 km) from the
center and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 70 miles
(110 km).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 989 mb (29.21 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 5 to 7 feet above normal tide levels near and to the
north of where Katia makes landfall. Near the coast, the surge will
be accompanied by large and destructive waves.

RAINFALL:  Katia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
5 to 10 inches over northern Veracruz, and 2 to 5 inches over far
southern Tamaulipas, northeast Puebla, and southern Veracruz through
Saturday morning. Isolated maximum amounts of 15 inches are possible
in northern Veracruz.  This rainfall may cause life-threatening
flash floods and mudslides, especially in areas of mountainous
terrain.

WIND:  Hurricane conditions are expected within portions of the
hurricane warning area by late Friday, with tropical storm
conditions expected within the tropical warning areas by
midday Friday.

SURF:  Swells generated by Katia are expected to affect portions of
the coast of southeastern Mexico today.  These swells are likely to
cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions. Please
consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 700 AM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 1000 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Blake

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
