<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL132017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>3</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>9</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170907 04:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170907 09:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709072100</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0400 PM CDT Thu Sep 07</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504818000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>KATIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>21.6</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-94.6</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>21.6N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>94.6W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>80</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>130</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>70</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>980</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.94</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>STATIONARY</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>0</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>0</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>0</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 215 MI...345 KM E OF TAMPICO MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 195 MI...315 KM NNE OF VERACRUZ MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT3 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Katia Advisory Number   9
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL132017
400 PM CDT Thu Sep 07 2017

...KATIA EXPECTED TO BEGIN MOVING TOWARD THE COAST OF MEXICO AND
STRENGTHEN TONIGHT OR EARLY FRIDAY...


SUMMARY OF 400 PM CDT...2100 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...21.6N 94.6W
ABOUT 215 MI...345 KM E OF TAMPICO MEXICO
ABOUT 195 MI...315 KM NNE OF VERACRUZ MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...80 MPH...130 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...STATIONARY
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...980 MB...28.94 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Cabo Rojo to Laguna Verde

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* North of Cabo Rojo to Rio Panuco
* South of Laguna Verde to Puerto Veracruz.

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area.  A warning is typically issued
36 hours before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-
storm-force winds, conditions that make outside preparations
difficult or dangerous.  Preparations to protect life and property
should be rushed to completion.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 400 PM CDT (2100 UTC), the center of Hurricane Katia was located
near latitude 21.6 North, longitude 94.6 West.  Katia is stationary
and little overall motion is anticipated through late today.
However, the hurricane is forecast to turn southwestward and
approach the coast within the warning area late Friday or early
Saturday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 80 mph (130 km/h) with higher
gusts.   Some strengthening is forecast during the next 36 hours and
Katia could be near major hurricane strength at landfall.

Katia is a small tropical cyclone.  Hurricane-force winds extend
outward up to 10 miles (20 km) from the center and
tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 45 miles (75 km).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 980 mb (28.94 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 5 to 7 feet above normal tide levels near and to the
north of where Katia makes landfall.  Near the coast, the surge will
be accompanied by large and destructive waves.

RAINFALL: Katia is expected to produce total rain accumulations
of 10 to 15 inches over northern Veracruz and eastern Hidalgo,
and Puebla.  Katia is also expected to produce total rain
accumulations of 2 to 5 inches over southern Tamaulipas, eastern
San Luis Potosi, western Hidalgo, eastern Queretaro, and southern
Veracruz through Saturday evening.  Isolated maximum amounts of 25
inches are possible in northern Veracruz and eastern Hidalgo,
Puebla, and San Luis Potosi.  This rainfall may cause
life-threatening flash floods and mudslides, especially in areas of
mountainous terrain.

WIND:  Hurricane conditions are expected within portions of the
hurricane warning area by Friday night or early Saturday, with
tropical storm conditions expected within the tropical storm warning
areas by late Friday.

SURF:  Swells generated by Katia are expected to affect portions of
the coast of southeastern Mexico today.  These swells are likely to
cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions. Please
consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 700 PM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 1000 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Pasch

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
