<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL132017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>3</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>13A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170908 07:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170909 12:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709090000</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 PM CDT Fri Sep 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504915200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>KATIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>20.9</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-96.8</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>20.9N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>96.8W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>105</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>165</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>90</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>972</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.71</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 2</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WSW OR 250 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>7</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>11</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>6</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 130 MI...210 KM SE OF TAMPICO MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 130 MI...210 KM N OF VERACRUZ MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT3 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Katia Intermediate Advisory Number 13A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL132017
Issued by the NWS Weather Prediction Center College Park MD
700 PM CDT Fri Sep 08 2017

...AIR FORCE PLANE EN ROUTE TO KATIA...
...DANGEROUS STORM SURGE EXPECTED IN MEXICO...


SUMMARY OF 700 PM CDT...0000 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...20.9N 96.8W
ABOUT 130 MI...210 KM SE OF TAMPICO MEXICO
ABOUT 130 MI...210 KM N OF VERACRUZ MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...105 MPH...165 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WSW OR 250 DEGREES AT 7 MPH...11 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...972 MB...28.71 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Cabo Rojo to Laguna Verde

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* North of Cabo Rojo to Rio Panuco
* South of Laguna Verde to Puerto Veracruz

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area.  Preparations to protect life and
property should be completed.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 PM CDT (0000 UTC), the center of Hurricane Katia was located
near latitude 20.9 North, longitude 96.8 West. Katia is moving
toward the west-southwest near 7 mph (11 km/h) and this motion is
expected to continue through Saturday. The center of Katia will make
landfall in Mexico late tonight or early Saturday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 105 mph (165 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Little change in strength is expected prior to landfall,
followed by rapid weakening thereafter.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 25 miles (35 km) from
the center and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 70
miles (110 km).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 972 mb (28.71 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge will raise water levels by
as much as 5 to 8 feet above normal tide levels near and to the
north of where Katia makes landfall.  Near the coast, the surge will
be accompanied by large and destructive waves.

RAINFALL:  Katia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
10 to 15 inches over northern Veracruz, eastern Hidalgo, and
Puebla.  Katia is also expected to produce total rain accumulations
of 2 to 5 inches over southern Tamaulipas, eastern San Luis Potosi,
western Hidalgo, eastern Queretaro, and southern Veracruz through
Saturday evening.  Isolated maximum amounts of 25 inches are
possible in northern Veracruz, eastern Hidalgo, Puebla, and San
Luis Potosi. This rainfall will likely cause life-threatening flash
floods and mudslides, especially in areas of mountainous terrain.

WIND:  Hurricane conditions are expected within portions of the
hurricane warning area tonight or early Saturday, with tropical
storm conditions expected to continue within the tropical storm
warning areas.

SURF:  Swells generated by Katia will continue to affect portions of
the coast of southeastern Mexico during the next couple of days.
These swells are likely to cause life-threatening surf and rip
current conditions. Please consult products from your local weather
office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Roth/Lamers/Blake

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
