<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL152017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>5</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>6</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170917 05:00:00 PM AST</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170917 09:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709172100</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0500 PM AST Sun Sep 17</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1505682000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>MARIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>13.8</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-57.5</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>13.8N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>57.5W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>75</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>120</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>65</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>982</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.00</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 285 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>15</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>24</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>13</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 140 MI...225 KM ENE OF BARBADOS</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 275 MI...445 KM ESE OF DOMINICA</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT5 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Maria Advisory Number   6
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL152017
500 PM AST Sun Sep 17 2017

...MARIA BECOMES A HURRICANE...
...ADDITIONAL WARNINGS AND WATCHES ISSUED FOR PORTIONS OF THE
LEEWARD ISLANDS...


SUMMARY OF 500 PM AST...2100 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...13.8N 57.5W
ABOUT 140 MI...225 KM ENE OF BARBADOS
ABOUT 275 MI...445 KM ESE OF DOMINICA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...75 MPH...120 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 285 DEGREES AT 15 MPH...24 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...982 MB...29.00 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of Antigua and Barbuda has issued a Hurricane
Warning for St. Kitts, Nevis, and Montserrat.

The government of Antigua and Barbuda has issued a Tropical Storm
Warning for Antigua and Barbuda.  The Hurricane Watch has been
discontinued for these islands.

The government of the Netherlands has issued a Tropical Storm
Warning for Saba and St. Eustatius.

A Hurricane Watch has been issued for the U.S. Virgin Islands.

The government of Antigua and Barbuda has issued a Hurricane Watch
for the British Virgin Islands.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Guadeloupe
* Dominica
* St. Kitts, Nevis, and Montserrat

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Martinique
* Antigua and Barbuda
* Saba and St. Eustatius
* St. Lucia

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* U.S. Virgin Islands
* British Virgin Islands
* Saba and St. Eustatius
* St. Maarten
* St. Martin and St. Barthelemy
* Anguilla

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* Barbados
* St. Vincent and the Grenadines

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area.  A warning is typically issued
36 hours before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-
force winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.  Preparations to protect life and property should be
rushed to completion.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.  A watch is typically issued 48 hours
before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-force
winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

Interests elsewhere in the Lesser Antilles and Puerto Rico should
monitor the progress of this system.  Additional Tropical Storm or
Hurricane Watches and Warnings will likely be issued tonight or on
Monday.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 500 PM AST (2100 UTC), the center of Hurricane Maria was located
by an Air Force Reserve reconnaissance aircraft near latitude 13.8
North, longitude 57.5 West.  Maria is moving toward the
west-northwest near 15 mph (24 km/h), and this motion with a
decrease in forward speed is expected through Tuesday.  On the
forecast track, the center of Maria will move across the Leeward
Islands Monday night and then over the extreme northeastern
Caribbean Sea on Tuesday.

Reconnaissance data indicate that maximum sustained winds have
increased to near 75 mph (120 km/h) with higher gusts.  Additional
strengthening is forecast during the next 48 hours, and Maria could
be near major hurricane intensity when it moves across the Leeward
Islands Monday night.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 15 miles (30 km) from the
center, and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 105
miles (165 km).

The minimum central pressure measured by the aircraft is 982 mb
(29.00 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Hurricane conditions are first expected within portions of
the Leeward Islands by Monday night, with tropical storm conditions
beginning on Monday.  Hurricane conditions are possible within the
hurricane watch area by Tuesday, with tropical storm conditions
possible Monday night.  Tropical storm conditions are possible in
the tropical storm watch area Monday or Monday night.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge accompanied by large and
destructive waves will raise water levels by as much as 4 to 6 feet
above normal tide levels near where the center of Maria moves
across the Leeward Islands.

RAINFALL:  Maria is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
6 to 12 inches with isolated maximum amounts of 20 inches across the
Leeward Islands, including Puerto Rico and the U.S. and
British Virgin Islands through Wednesday night.  Maria is also
expected to produce total rain accumulations of 2 to 4 inches for
the northern and central Windward Islands.  In all the above areas,
these rainfall amounts could cause life-threatening flash floods and
mudslides.

SURF:  Swells generated by Maria are affecting the Lesser Antilles.
These swells are likely to cause life-threatening surf and rip
current conditions.  Please consult products from your local
weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 800 PM AST.
Next complete advisory at 1100 PM AST.

$$
Forecaster Berg

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
