<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL152017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>5</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>46</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170927 11:00:00 AM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170927 03:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709271500</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1100 AM EDT Wed Sep 27</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1506524400</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>MARIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>35.6</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-72.6</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>35.6N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>72.6W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>75</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>120</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>65</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>978</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.88</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNE OR 15 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>6</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>9</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>5</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 165 MI...265 KM E OF CAPE HATTERAS NORTH CAROLINA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT5 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Maria Advisory Number  46
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL152017
1100 AM EDT Wed Sep 27 2017

...MARIA TURNS NORTH-NORTHEASTWARD...


SUMMARY OF 1100 AM EDT...1500 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...35.6N 72.6W
ABOUT 165 MI...265 KM E OF CAPE HATTERAS NORTH CAROLINA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...75 MPH...120 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNE OR 15 DEGREES AT 6 MPH...9 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...978 MB...28.88 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Tropical Storm Warning has been discontinued west of Ocracoke
Inlet.

The Storm Surge Watch has been discontinued west of Ocracoke Inlet.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for...
* Ocracoke Inlet to Cape Hatteras

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Ocracoke Inlet to the North Carolina/Virginia border
* Albemarle and Pamlico Sounds

A Storm Surge Watch is in effect for...
* North of Cape Hatteras to Duck

A Storm Surge Warning means there is a danger of life-threatening
inundation, from rising water moving inland from the coastline in
the indicated locations. For a depiction of areas at risk, please
see the National Weather Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic,
available at hurricanes.gov.  This is a life-threatening situation.
Persons located within these areas should take all necessary actions
to protect life and property from rising water and the potential for
other dangerous conditions.  Promptly follow evacuation and other
instructions from local officials.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area.

A Storm Surge Watch means there is a possibility of life-
threatening inundation, from rising water moving inland from the
coastline in the indicated locations. For a depiction of areas at
risk, please see the National Weather Service Storm Surge
Watch/Warning Graphic, available at hurricanes.gov.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1100 AM EDT (1500 UTC), the center of Hurricane Maria was located
near latitude 35.6 North, longitude 72.6 West. Maria is moving
toward the north-northeast near 6 mph (9 km/h), and this motion is
expected to continue today. Maria is forecast to accelerate
east-northeastward on Thursday and Thursday night. On the forecast
track, Maria will begin to move away from the coast of North
Carolina later today and tonight.

Reports from an Air Force Reserve reconnaissance aircraft indicate
that the maximum sustained winds are near 75 mph (120 km/h) with
higher gusts.  Some weakening is forecast during the next 48 hours.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 105 miles (165 km)
primary to the northeast of the center, and tropical-storm-force
winds extend outward up to 230 miles (370 km). An observing site at
Jennette's Pier in Nags Head, North Carolina, recently reported a
sustained wind of 43 mph (69 km/h) and a gust of 51 mph (81 km/h).

The estimated minimum central pressure based on reconnaissance
aircraft data is 978 mb (28.88 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected within the warning
area through today.

STORM SURGE:  The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the
tide will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by
rising waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is
expected to reach the following heights above ground if the peak
surge occurs at the time of high tide...

Ocracoke Inlet to Duck including the sound side of the Outer
Banks...2 to 4 ft

Surge-related flooding depends on the relative timing of the surge
and the tidal cycle, and can vary greatly over short distances.  For
information specific to your area, please see products issued by
your local National Weather Service forecast office.

SURF:  Large swells generated by Maria are affecting much of the
east coast of the United States, Atlantic Canada, Bermuda, the
Bahamas, and the Turks and Caicos Islands.  These swells are likely
to cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions.  Please
consult products from your local weather office for more
information.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 200 PM EDT.
Next complete advisory at 500 PM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Brown

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
