<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL152017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>5</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>37A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170925 08:00:00 AM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170925 12:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709251200</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0800 AM EDT Mon Sep 25</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1506340800</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>MARIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>30.8</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-73</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>30.8N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>73.0W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>75</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>120</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>65</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>961</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.38</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>N OR 355 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>7</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>11</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>6</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 335 MI...540 KM SSE OF CAPE HATTERAS NORTH CAROLINA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT5 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Maria Intermediate Advisory Number 37A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL152017
800 AM EDT Mon Sep 25 2017

...MARIA CONTINUES TO MOVE SLOWLY NORTHWARD...
...LARGE SWELLS AFFECTING MUCH OF THE EAST COAST OF THE UNITED
STATES...


SUMMARY OF 800 AM EDT...1200 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...30.8N 73.0W
ABOUT 335 MI...540 KM SSE OF CAPE HATTERAS NORTH CAROLINA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...75 MPH...120 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...N OR 355 DEGREES AT 7 MPH...11 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...961 MB...28.38 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Cape Lookout to Duck
* Albemarle and Pamlico Sounds

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* North of Duck to the North Carolina/Virginia border
* North of Surf City to south of Cape Lookout

A Storm Surge Watch is in effect for...
* Cape Lookout to Duck

Interests elsewhere along the Carolina and Mid-Atlantic coasts
should monitor the progress of Maria.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, in this case within the next 36
to 48 hours.

A Storm Surge Watch means there is a possibility of life-
threatening inundation, from rising water moving inland from the
coastline, in the indicated locations during the next 48 hours.
For a depiction of areas at risk, please see the National Weather
Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic, available at
hurricanes.gov.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 800 AM EDT (1200 UTC), the center of Hurricane Maria was located
near latitude 30.8 North, longitude 73.0 West. Maria is moving
toward the north near 7 mph (11 km/h), and this general motion with
some decrease in forward speed is expected through Tuesday night. On
the forecast track, the center of Maria will move well east of the
southeast coast of the United States during the next day or so.

Reports from reconnaissance aircraft indicate that maximum
sustained winds have decreased to near 75 mph (120 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Additional weakening is forecast during the next 48 hours,
and Maria is expected to weaken to a tropical storm by Tuesday
night.

Maria is a large hurricane.  Hurricane-force winds extend outward
up to 70 miles (110 km) mainly to the east of the center and
tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 230 miles (370 km).

The latest minimum central pressure reported by an Air Force
Reserve Hurricane Hunter aircraft is 961 mb (28.38 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected within the
warning area beginning Tuesday.  Tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area beginning Tuesday.

STORM SURGE:  The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the
tide will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by
rising waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is
expected to reach the following heights above ground if the peak
surge occurs at the time of high tide...

Cape Lookout to Duck including the sound side of the Outer
Banks...2 to 4 ft

Surge-related flooding depends on the relative timing of the surge
and the tidal cycle, and can vary greatly over short distances.  For
information specific to your area, please see products issued by
your local National Weather Service forecast office.

RAINFALL...Maria is expected to produce total rainfall accumulations
of 1 to 2 inches over the Outer Banks of North Carolina through
Wednesday.

SURF:  Swells generated by Maria are affecting portions of the
coast of the southeastern United States and Bermuda and will be
increasing along the coasts of the Mid-Atlantic and southern New
England today. Swells also continue to affect Puerto Rico, portions
of the Virgin Islands, the northern coast of Hispaniola, the Turks
and Caicos Islands, and the Bahamas.  These swells are likely to
cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions.  Please
consult products from your local weather office for more
information.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1100 AM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Brown

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
