<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL152017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>5</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>44</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170926 11:00:00 PM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170927 03:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709270300</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1100 PM EDT Tue Sep 26</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1506481200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>MARIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>34.9</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-72.9</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>34.9N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>72.9W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>70</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>110</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>60</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>975</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.80</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>N OR 5 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>7</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>11</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>6</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 150 MI...240 KM E OF CAPE HATTERAS NORTH CAROLINA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT5 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Maria Advisory Number  44
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL152017
1100 PM EDT Tue Sep 26 2017

...GUSTY WINDS CONTINUING OVER THE OUTER BANKS OF NORTH
CAROLINA...


SUMMARY OF 1100 PM EDT...0300 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...34.9N 72.9W
ABOUT 150 MI...240 KM E OF CAPE HATTERAS NORTH CAROLINA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...70 MPH...110 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...N OR 5 DEGREES AT 7 MPH...11 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...975 MB...28.80 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for...
* Ocracoke Inlet to Cape Hatteras

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Bogue Inlet to the North Carolina/Virginia border
* Albemarle and Pamlico Sounds

A Storm Surge Watch is in effect for...
* Cape Lookout to west of Ocracoke Inlet
* North of Cape Hatteras to Duck

A Storm Surge Warning means there is a danger of life-threatening
inundation, from rising water moving inland from the coastline in
the indicated locations. For a depiction of areas at risk, please
see the National Weather Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic,
available at hurricanes.gov.  This is a life-threatening situation.
Persons located within these areas should take all necessary actions
to protect life and property from rising water and the potential for
other dangerous conditions.  Promptly follow evacuation and other
instructions from local officials.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area.

A Storm Surge Watch means there is a possibility of life-
threatening inundation, from rising water moving inland from the
coastline in the indicated locations. For a depiction of areas at
risk, please see the National Weather Service Storm Surge
Watch/Warning Graphic, available at hurricanes.gov.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1100 PM EDT (0300 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Maria was
located near latitude 34.9 North, longitude 72.9 West.  Maria is
moving toward the north near 7 mph (11 km/h), and this general
motion with some decrease in forward speed is expected overnight.
A turn toward the north-northeast is expected on Wednesday, and a
turn toward the east-northeast is anticipated on Thursday.  On the
forecast track, the center of Maria will pass east of the coast of
North Carolina during the next day or so.

Maximum sustained winds are near 70 mph (110 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Some slight weakening is forecast during the next day or
two.

Maria is a large tropical storm.  Tropical-storm-force winds extend
outward up to 230 miles (370 km) from the center.  Hatteras
Landing, on the North Carolina Outer Banks, recently reported a
sustained wind of 37 mph (59 km/h) with a gust to 46 mph (70 km/h).

The minimum central pressure estimated from Air Force Hurricane
Hunter aircraft observations is 975 mb (28.80 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected within the warning
through Wednesday.

STORM SURGE:  The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the
tide will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by
rising waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is
expected to reach the following heights above ground if the peak
surge occurs at the time of high tide...

Cape Lookout to Duck including the sound side of the Outer
Banks...2 to 4 ft

Surge-related flooding depends on the relative timing of the surge
and the tidal cycle, and can vary greatly over short distances.  For
information specific to your area, please see products issued by
your local National Weather Service forecast office.

RAINFALL:  Maria is expected to produce total rain accumulations
of 1 to 2 inches over the Outer Banks of North Carolina through
Wednesday.

SURF:  Large swells generated by Maria are affecting much of the
east coast of the United States.  These swells are also affecting
Bermuda, the Turks and Caicos Islands, and the Bahamas.  These
swells are likely to cause life-threatening surf and rip current
conditions.  Please consult products from your local weather office
for more information.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 200 AM EDT.
Next complete advisory at 500 AM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Pasch

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
