<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL152017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>5</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>7</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170917 11:00:00 PM AST</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170918 03:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709180300</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1100 PM AST Sun Sep 17</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1505703600</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>MARIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>14.2</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-58.4</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>14.2N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>58.4W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>85</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>140</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>75</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>979</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>28.91</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>WNW OR 290 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>13</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>20</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>11</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 100 MI...165 KM NE OF BARBADOS</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 210 MI...340 KM ESE OF DOMINICA</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT5 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Maria Advisory Number   7
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL152017
1100 PM AST Sun Sep 17 2017

...MARIA FORECAST TO BECOME A MAJOR HURRICANE AS IT MOVES NEAR
THE LEEWARD ISLANDS...


SUMMARY OF 1100 PM AST...0300 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...14.2N 58.4W
ABOUT 100 MI...165 KM NE OF BARBADOS
ABOUT 210 MI...340 KM ESE OF DOMINICA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...85 MPH...140 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...WNW OR 290 DEGREES AT 13 MPH...20 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...979 MB...28.91 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Guadeloupe
* Dominica
* St. Kitts, Nevis, and Montserrat
* Martinique

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Antigua and Barbuda
* Saba and St. Eustatius
* St. Lucia

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* U.S. Virgin Islands
* British Virgin Islands
* Saba and St. Eustatius
* St. Maarten
* St. Martin and St. Barthelemy
* Anguilla

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* Barbados
* St. Vincent and the Grenadines

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area.  Preparations to protect life and
property should be rushed to completion.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.  A watch is typically issued 48 hours
before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-force
winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

Interests elsewhere in the Lesser Antilles, Puerto Rico, and the
Dominican Republic should monitor the progress of this system.
Additional Hurricane and Tropical storm Warnings may be issued for
portion of the Leeward and Virgin Islands on Monday, and
Hurricane Watches will likely be issued for Puerto Rico and the
nearby islands Monday morning.

For storm information specific to your area in the United
States, including possible inland watches and warnings, please
monitor products issued by your local National Weather Service
forecast office. For storm information specific to your area outside
the United States, please monitor products issued by your national
meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1100 PM AST (0300 UTC), the center of Hurricane Maria was located
near latitude 14.2 North, longitude 58.4 West. Maria is moving
toward the west-northwest near 13 mph (20 km/h), and this motion
with a decrease in forward speed is expected through Tuesday night.
On the forecast track, the center of Maria will move across the
Leeward Islands late Monday and Monday night and then over the
extreme northeastern Caribbean Sea Tuesday and Tuesday night.

Maximum sustained winds have increased to near 85 mph (140 km/h)
with higher gusts.  Rapid strengthening is forecast during the next
48 hours, and Maria is expected to become a major hurricane as it
moves through the Leeward Islands.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 15 miles (30 km) from the
center and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 105 miles
(165 km).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 979 mb (28.91 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Hurricane conditions are first expected within portions of
the Leeward Islands by late Monday, with tropical storm conditions
beginning during the day on Monday.  Hurricane conditions are
possible within the hurricane watch area by Tuesday, with tropical
storm conditions possible Monday night.  Tropical storm conditions
are possible in the tropical storm watch area later tonight through
Monday night.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge accompanied by large and
destructive waves will raise water levels by as much as 5 to 7 feet
above normal tide levels near where the center of Maria moves
across the Leeward Islands.

RAINFALL: Maria is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
6 to 12 inches with isolated maximum amounts of 20 inches across the
central and southern Leeward Islands, including Puerto Rico and the
U.S. and British Virgin Islands, through Wednesday night.  Maria is
also expected to produce total rain accumulations of 2 to 4 inches
with isolated maximum amounts of 8 inches over the remaining
northern Leeward Islands from Barbuda to Anguilla, as well as the
Windward Islands and Barbados.  Rainfall on all of these islands
could cause life-threatening flash floods and mudslides.

SURF:  Swells generated by Maria are affecting the Lesser Antilles.
These swells are likely to cause life-threatening surf and rip
current conditions.  Please consult products from your local
weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 200 AM AST.
Next complete advisory at 500 AM AST.

$$
Forecaster Beven

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
