<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL162017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>1</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>16A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20171008 07:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20171008 12:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201710081200</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 AM CDT Sun Oct 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1507464000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>NATE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>32.0</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-88</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>32.0N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>88.0W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>45</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>75</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>40</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>994</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.35</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNE OR 25 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>23</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>37</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>20</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM ESE OF MERIDIAN MISSISSIPPI</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 95 MI...155 KM WSW OF MONTGOMERY ALABAMA</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT1 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Nate Intermediate Advisory Number 16A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL162017
700 AM CDT Sun Oct 08 2017

...NATE RAPIDLY WEAKENING BUT STORM SURGE FLOODING CONTINUES...
...HEAVY RAINFALL SPREADING OVER THE SOUTHEASTERN UNITED STATES...


SUMMARY OF 700 AM CDT...1200 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...32.0N 88.0W
ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM ESE OF MERIDIAN MISSISSIPPI
ABOUT 95 MI...155 KM WSW OF MONTGOMERY ALABAMA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...45 MPH...75 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNE OR 25 DEGREES AT 23 MPH...37 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...994 MB...29.35 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Storm Surge Warning has been discontinued west of the
Mississippi/Alabama border.

The Tropical Storm Warning has been discontinued west of the
Alabama/Florida border.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for...
* Mississippi/Alabama border to the Okaloosa/Walton County Line
Florida

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Alabama/Florida border eastward to Indian Pass Florida

A Storm Surge Warning means there is a danger of life-threatening
inundation, from rising water moving inland from the coastline in
the indicated locations. For a depiction of areas at risk, please
see the National Weather Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic,
available at hurricanes.gov.  This is a life-threatening situation.
Persons located within these areas should take all necessary actions
to protect life and property from rising water and the potential for
other dangerous conditions.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 AM CDT (1200 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Nate was
located by NOAA Doppler weather radars and surface observations near
latitude 32.0 North, longitude 88.0 West.  Nate is moving toward the
north-northeast near 23 mph (37 km/h). A turn toward the northeast
with an increase in forward speed is expected during the next couple
of days.  On the forecast track, Nate's center will continue to move
inland across the Deep South, Tennessee Valley, and central
Appalachian Mountains through Monday.

Maximum sustained winds have decreased to near 45 mph (75 km/h)
with higher gusts.  Nate is expected to continue to quickly weaken
as it moves farther inland. It should degenerate into a remnant low
late Monday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 150 miles (150 km)
primarily southeast of the center over water. A wind gust to 58 mph
(93 km/h) was reported at Destin, Florida within the past couple of
hours.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 994 mb (29.35 inches).

Water levels of around 3.0 to 3.5 ft above Mean Higher High Water
(MHHW) have recently been reported by National Ocean Service gauges
at Pensacola, Florida, and Mobile Bay, Alabama.


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected to continue in the
tropical storm warning area for the next couple of hours.

STORM SURGE: The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the tide
will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by rising
waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is expected to
reach the following heights above ground if the peak surge occurs at
the time of high tide...

Mississippi/Alabama border to the Alabama/Florida border, including
Mobile Bay...5 to 8 ft
Alabama/Florida border to the Okaloosa/Walton County Line...3 to 5
ft
Morgan City, Louisiana to the Mississippi/Alabama border...1 to 3 ft
Okaloosa/Walton County Line to Indian Pass, Florida...2 to 3 ft
Indian Pass to Crystal River, Florida...1 to 3 ft

The deepest water will occur along the immediate coast near and to
the east of the landfall location, where the surge will be
accompanied by large and destructive waves.  Surge-related
flooding depends on the relative timing of the surge and the tidal
cycle, and can vary greatly over short distances.  For information
specific to your area, please see products issued by your local
National Weather Service forecast office.

RAINFALL:  Nate is expected to produce the following rain
accumulations through Monday:

East of the Mississippi River from the central Gulf Coast into the
Deep South, eastern Tennessee Valley, and southern Appalachians:
3 to 6 inches, max 10 inches.

Across the Ohio Valley into the central Appalachians:
2 to 5 inches, max 7 inches.

TORNADOES:  Isolated tornadoes are possible today, mainly from the
Florida Panhandle and eastern Alabama across western and northern
Georgia.

SURF:  Swells generated by Nate will affect land areas around the
Gulf of Mexico through this evening.  These swells are likely
to cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions. Please
consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Brown

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
