<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL162017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>1</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>5A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20171005 02:00:00 PM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20171005 06:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201710051800</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0200 PM EDT Thu Oct 05</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1507226400</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>NATE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>14.5</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-84</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>14.5N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>84.0W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>40</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>65</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>35</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>1001</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.56</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 325 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>9</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>15</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>8</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM NW OF PUERTO CABEZAS NICARAGUA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM SSW OF PUERTO LEMPIRA HONDURAS</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT1 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Nate Intermediate Advisory Number 5A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL162017
200 PM EDT Thu Oct 05 2017

...CENTER OF NATE CONTINUES MOVING ACROSS NORTHEASTERN NICARAGUA...
...FLOODING RAINS EXPECTED OVER PORTIONS OF CENTRAL AMERICA...


SUMMARY OF 200 PM EDT...1800 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...14.5N 84.0W
ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM NW OF PUERTO CABEZAS NICARAGUA
ABOUT 50 MI...80 KM SSW OF PUERTO LEMPIRA HONDURAS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...40 MPH...65 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 325 DEGREES AT 9 MPH...15 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...1001 MB...29.56 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Sandy Bay Sirpi Nicaragua to Punta Castilla Honduras
* Punta Herrero to Rio Lagartos Mexico

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* Punta Herrero to Rio Lagartos Mexico

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area.

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.

Interests elsewhere in Honduras, the Bay Islands, western Cuba, the
Yucatan Peninsula, and the northern coast of the Gulf of Mexico
should monitor the progress of Nate.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 200 PM EDT (1800 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Nate was
located inland over northeastern Nicaragua near latitude 14.5 North,
longitude 84.0 West.  Nate is moving toward the northwest near 9 mph
(15 km/h).  A turn toward the north-northwest at a faster forward
speed is expected this afternoon or tonight, with that motion
continuing through Friday night.  On the forecast track, the center
of Nate should move across northeastern Nicaragua and eastern
Honduras this afternoon and then over the northwestern Caribbean Sea
tonight and Friday.  The center is expected to approach the coast of
the Yucatan Peninsula late Friday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 40 mph (65 km/h) with higher
gusts. Little change in strength is expected today while the center
is over land.  Strengthening is likely once the center moves over
the northwestern Caribbean Sea tonight and Friday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 50 miles (80 km)
mainly over water to the east of the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 1001 mb (29.56 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Nate is expected to produce the following rain
accumulations through Friday night:

Nicaragua...15 to 20 inches, isolated 30 inches
Costa Rica and Panama...5 to 10 inches, isolated 20 inches
Honduras and Eastern portions of the Yucatan Peninsula...4 to 8
inches, isolated 12 inches
Belize...2 to 5 inches, isolated 8 inches

Heavy rainfall will occur over a wide area, including locations well
away from the center along the Pacific coast of Central America.
Rainfall across all of these areas may produce life-threatening
flash floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected within portions of the
warning area in Nicaragua and Honduras today and tonight.  Hurricane
conditions are possible within the hurricane watch area in Mexico
Friday night, with tropical storm conditions expected by late
Friday.

SURF:  Swells generated by Nate are affecting portions of the coast
of Nicaragua, and will begin to affect other land areas around the
northwestern Caribbean during the next day or two.  These swells are
likely to cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions.
Please consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 500 PM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Beven

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
