<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL162017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>1</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>16</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20171008 04:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20171008 09:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201710080900</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0400 AM CDT Sun Oct 08</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1507453200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>NATE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>31.5</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-88.4</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>31.5N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>88.4W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>70</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>110</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>60</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>986</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.12</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNE OR 25 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>23</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>37</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>20</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 80 MI...130 KM NNE OF BILOXI MISSISSIPPI</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 135 MI...215 KM WSW OF MONTGOMERY ALABAMA</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT1 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM CCA

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Nate Advisory Number  16...Corrected
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL162017
400 AM CDT Sun Oct 08 2017

Corrected Storm Surge breakpoint in Hazards section

...NATE MOVING FARTHER INLAND OVER MISSISSIPPI AND ALABAMA...
...RAPID WEAKENING ANTICIPATED...


SUMMARY OF 400 AM CDT...0900 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...31.5N 88.4W
ABOUT 80 MI...130 KM NNE OF BILOXI MISSISSIPPI
ABOUT 135 MI...215 KM WSW OF MONTGOMERY ALABAMA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...70 MPH...110 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNE OR 25 DEGREES AT 23 MPH...37 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...986 MB...29.12 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Hurricane Warning for Mouth of the Pearl River to the
Alabama/Florida border has been discontinued.

The Tropical Storm Warning west of the Mouth of the Pearl River,
including Metropolitan New Orleans, and Lakes Pontchartrain and
Maurepas has been discontinued.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for...
* North of Pointe a la Hache to the Okaloosa/Walton County Line
Florida

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Mouth of Pearl River eastward to Indian Pass Florida

A Storm Surge Warning means there is a danger of life-threatening
inundation, from rising water moving inland from the coastline in
the indicated locations. For a depiction of areas at risk, please
see the National Weather Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic,
available at hurricanes.gov.  This is a life-threatening situation.
Persons located within these areas should take all necessary actions
to protect life and property from rising water and the potential for
other dangerous conditions.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 400 AM CDT (0900 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Nate was
located near latitude 31.5 North, longitude 88.4 West. Nate is
moving toward the north-northeast near 23 mph (37 km/h). A turn
toward the northeast with an increase in forward speed is expected
during the next couple of days.  On the forecast track, Nate's
center will continue to move inland across the Deep South, Tennessee
Valley, and central Appalachian Mountains through Monday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 70 mph (110 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Nate is expected to continue to quickly weaken as it moves
farther inland. It should degenerate into a remnant low late
Monday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 90 miles (150 km)
from the center. Mobile airport recently reported a wind gust of
54 mph (87 km/h).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 986 mb (29.12 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected to continue in the
tropical storm warning area for the next several hours.

STORM SURGE: The combination of a dangerous storm surge and the tide
will cause normally dry areas near the coast to be flooded by rising
waters moving inland from the shoreline.  The water is expected to
reach the following heights above ground if the peak surge occurs at
the time of high tide...

Mouth of the Pearl River to the Alabama/Florida border, including
Mobile Bay...5 to 8 ft
North of Pointe a la Hache to the mouth of the Pearl River...4 to 6
ft.
Alabama/Florida border to the Okaloosa/Walton County Line...3 to 5
ft
Morgan City, Louisiana to Pointe a la Hache...1 to 3 ft
Okaloosa/Walton County Line to Indian Pass, Florida...2 to 3 ft
Indian Pass to Crystal River, Florida...1 to 3 ft

The deepest water will occur along the immediate coast near and to
the east of the landfall location, where the surge will be
accompanied by large and destructive waves.  Surge-related
flooding depends on the relative timing of the surge and the tidal
cycle, and can vary greatly over short distances.  For information
specific to your area, please see products issued by your local
National Weather Service forecast office.

RAINFALL:  Nate is expected to produce the following rain
accumulations through Monday:

East of the Mississippi River from the central Gulf Coast into the
Deep South, eastern Tennessee Valley, and southern Appalachians:
3 to 6 inches, max 10 inches.

Across the Ohio Valley into the central Appalachians:
2 to 5 inches, max 7 inches.

TORNADOES:  Isolated tornadoes are possible today, mainly from the
Florida Panhandle and eastern Alabama across western and northern
Georgia.

SURF:  Swells generated by Nate will affect land areas around the
Gulf of Mexico through this evening.  These swells are likely
to cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions. Please
consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 700 AM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 1000 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Avila

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
