<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL162017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>1</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>10A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20171006 07:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20171007 12:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201710070000</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 PM CDT Fri Oct 06</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1507334400</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>NATE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>21.4</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-85.9</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>21.4N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>85.9W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>65</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>100</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>55</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>990</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.23</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNW OR 340 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>22</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>35</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>19</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 90 MI...145 KM NE OF COZUMEL MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 570 MI...915 KM SSE OF THE MOUTH OF THE MISSISSIPPI RIVER</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT1 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Nate Intermediate Advisory Number 10A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL162017
700 PM CDT Fri Oct 06 2017

...HURRICANE HUNTER PLANES FIND NATE A LITTLE STRONGER...
...CENTER NOW MOVING THROUGH THE YUCATAN CHANNEL...


SUMMARY OF 700 PM CDT...0000 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...21.4N 85.9W
ABOUT 90 MI...145 KM NE OF COZUMEL MEXICO
ABOUT 570 MI...915 KM SSE OF THE MOUTH OF THE MISSISSIPPI RIVER
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...65 MPH...100 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNW OR 340 DEGREES AT 22 MPH...35 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...990 MB...29.23 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Grand Isle Louisiana to the Alabama/Florida border
* Metropolitan New Orleans and Lake Pontchartrain

A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for...
* Morgan City Louisiana to the Okaloosa/Walton County Line Florida
* Northern and western shores of Lake Pontchartrain

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Punta Herrero to Rio Lagartos Mexico
* Pinar del Rio Cuba
* Lake Maurepas
* West of Grand Isle to Morgan City Louisiana
* East of the Alabama/Florida border to the Okaloosa/Walton County
Line.

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* Punta Herrero to Rio Lagartos Mexico
* Lake Maurepas
* East of the Alabama/Florida border to the Okaloosa/Walton County
Line
* West of Grand Isle to Morgan City Louisiana

A Storm Surge Watch is in effect for...
* East of the the Okaloosa/Walton County Line to Indian Pass Florida

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* East of the Okaloosa/Walton County Line to Indian Pass Florida
* West of Morgan City to Intracoastal City Louisiana
* Isle of Youth Cuba

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area.  A warning is typically issued
36 hours before the anticipated first occurrence of tropical-storm-
force winds, conditions that make outside preparations difficult or
dangerous.  Preparations to protect life and property should be
rushed to completion.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area.

A Storm Surge Watch means there is a possibility of life-
threatening inundation, from rising water moving inland from the
coastline, in the indicated locations during the next 48 hours.
For a depiction of areas at risk, please see the National Weather
Service Storm Surge Watch/Warning Graphic, available at
hurricanes.gov.

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

Interests elsewhere in western Cuba, the Yucatan Peninsula, and the
northern coast of the Gulf of Mexico should monitor the progress of
Nate.

For storm information specific to your area in the United States,
including possible inland watches and warnings, please monitor
products issued by your local National Weather Service forecast
office. For storm information specific to your area outside the
United States, please monitor products issued by your national
meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 PM CDT (0000 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Nate was
located by NOAA and Air Force Reserve Hurricane Hunter planes near
latitude 21.4 North, longitude 85.9 West.  Nate is moving toward the
north-northwest near 22 mph (35 km/h), and this motion is expected
to continue through Saturday, with a turn toward the north and
northeast expected Saturday night and Sunday.  On the forecast
track, the center of Nate will move near the northeastern coast of
the Yucatan peninsula this evening.  Nate will then move into the
southern Gulf of Mexico tonight, approach the northern Gulf coast
Saturday, and then make landfall over the northern Gulf coast
Saturday night or Sunday.

Reports from the reconnaissance planes indicate that maximum
sustained winds have increased to near 65 mph (100 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Additional strengthening is forecast during the next 36
hours, and Nate is expected to become a hurricane by the time it
reaches the northern Gulf of Mexico.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 125 miles (205 km)
mainly to the east of the center.

The minimum central pressure based on data from the aircraft is 990
mb (29.23 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Nate is expected to produce the following rain
accumulations through Monday:

Western Nicaragua, Honduras, and El Salvador: Lingering inflow bands
will bring additional 2-4 inches, max 6 inches.
Eastern Yucatan and western Cuba: 2 to 4 inches, max 6 inches.
Eastern Belize and the Cayman Islands: 1 to 3 inches.

East of the Mississippi River from the central Gulf Coast into the
Deep South, eastern Tennessee Valley, and southern Appalachians:
3 to 6 inches, max 10 inches.

Across the lower Ohio Valley into the central Appalachians:
2 to 4 inches, max 6 inches.

Heavy rainfall will occur over a wide area, including locations well
away from the center along the Pacific coast of Central America.
Rainfall across all of these areas may produce life-threatening
flash floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Hurricane conditions are possible within the hurricane watch
area in Mexico tonight, with tropical storm conditions expected
during the next few hours.  Tropical storm conditions are expected
in the warning area in Cuba tonight, and are possible in the
watch area in Cuba tonight.

Along the northern Gulf Coast, hurricane conditions are expected in
the hurricane warning area Saturday night, with tropical storm
conditions expected by late Saturday. Tropical storm conditions are
expected in the tropical storm warning area by Saturday night.
Hurricane conditions are possible in the hurricane watch area
Saturday night, and tropical storm conditions are possible in the
tropical storm watch area Saturday night and Sunday.

STORM SURGE: In the United States, the combination of a dangerous
storm surge and the tide will cause normally dry areas near the
coast to be flooded by rising waters moving inland from the
shoreline.  The water is expected to reach the following heights
above ground if the peak surge occurs at the time of high tide...

Morgan City, Louisiana to the mouth of the Mississippi River...4 to
6 ft
Mouth of the Mississippi River to the Alabama/Florida border...5 to
8 ft
Alabama/Florida border to the Okaloosa/Walton County Line...4 to 6
ft
Okaloosa/Walton County Line to Indian Pass, Florida...2 to 4 ft
Indian Pass to Crystal River, Florida...1 to 3 ft

The deepest water will occur along the immediate coast near and to
the east of the landfall location, where the surge will be
accompanied by large and destructive waves.  Surge-related
flooding depends on the relative timing of the surge and the tidal
cycle, and can vary greatly over short distances.  For information
specific to your area, please see products issued by your local
National Weather Service forecast office.

In Mexico, a storm surge will raise water levels by as much as 1
to 3 feet above normal tide levels along the immediate coast in
areas of onshore winds on the Yucatan Peninsula and the adjacent
islands.  Near the coast, the surge will be accompanied by large and
destructive waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Nate will affect land areas around the
northwestern Caribbean during the next day or so.  These swells are
likely to cause life-threatening surf and rip current conditions.
Please consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Berg

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
