<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL182017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>3</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>6A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20171029 02:00:00 AM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20171029 06:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201710290600</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0200 AM EDT Sun Oct 29</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1509256800</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>PHILIPPE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>24.6</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-82</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>24.6N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>82.0W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>45</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>75</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>40</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>1000</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.53</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>E OR 100 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>12</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>19</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>10</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 15 MI...25 KM W OF KEY WEST FLORIDA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT3 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Philippe Intermediate Advisory Number 6A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL182017
200 AM EDT Sun Oct 29 2017

...PHILIPPE MOVING ERRATICALLY NEAR KEY WEST...


SUMMARY OF 200 AM EDT...0600 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...24.6N 82.0W
ABOUT 15 MI...25 KM W OF KEY WEST FLORIDA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...45 MPH...75 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...E OR 100 DEGREES AT 12 MPH...19 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...1000 MB...29.53 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Cuban provinces of Isla de la Juventud, La Habana, Ciudad de la
Habana, Matanzas, Cienfuegos, and Villa Clara
* Northwestern Bahamas

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* Craig Key to Golden Beach
* Central Bahamas

For storm information specific to your area in the United
States, including possible inland watches and warnings, please
monitor products issued by your local National Weather Service
forecast office.  For storm information specific to your area
outside the United States, please monitor products issued by your
national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 200 AM EDT (0600 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Philippe was
located near latitude 24.6 North, longitude 82.0 West.  Philippe
has been moving erratically eastward near 12 mph (19 km/h).  A
turn toward the northeast is expected during the next few hours, and
a rapid motion toward the northeast is expected through Monday.
On the forecast track, the center of Philippe will move across the
Florida Keys or the southern tip of the Florida peninsula this
morning, and across the northwestern Bahamas later today.

Maximum sustained winds have increased to near 45 mph (75 km/h) with
higher gusts.  Some strengthening is forecast during the next 48
hours.  However, Philippe is expected to become a post-tropical
cyclone by Monday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 105 miles (165 km)
mainly to the east and southeast of the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 1000 mb (29.53 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL: Across the northern Bahamas and south Florida including
the Keys rainfall amounts of 3 to 5 inches with isolated maximum
totals of 8 inches are expected through today.  These rainfall
totals may produce flash flooding, especially in urbanized areas.

Additional rainfall amounts of 1 to 2 inches are possible across
portions of central Cuba, which may lead to life-threatening flash
floods and mudslides in the higher terrain.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are likely occurring over portions
of the warning area in Cuba.  Tropical storm conditions are
expected to occur in the warning area later this morning across the
northwestern Bahamas.  Tropical storm conditions are possible across
portions of the Florida Keys and southeast Florida over the next
several hours, and in the central Bahamas later this morning.

TORNADOES:  An isolated tornado or two is possible across far South
Florida and the Florida Keys this morning.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 500 AM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Pasch

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
