<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL182017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>3</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>6</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20171028 11:00:00 PM EDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20171029 03:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201710290300</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1100 PM EDT Sat Oct 28</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1509246000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>PHILIPPE</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>24.8</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-82.1</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>24.8N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>82.1W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>40</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>65</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>35</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>1003</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.62</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNE OR 15 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>24</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>39</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>21</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 25 MI...40 KM NW OF KEY WEST FLORIDA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT3 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM CCA

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Philippe Advisory Number   6...Corrected
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL182017
1100 PM EDT Sat Oct 28 2017

CORRECTED SECOND HEADLINE

...CENTER OF POORLY ORGANIZED PHILIPPE APPROACHING THE FLORIDA
KEYS...
...HEAVY RAINS OCCURRING FROM CENTRAL CUBA ACROSS SOUTHERN FLORIDA
TO THE NORTHWESTERN BAHAMAS...


SUMMARY OF 1100 PM EDT...0300 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...24.8N 82.1W
ABOUT 25 MI...40 KM NW OF KEY WEST FLORIDA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...40 MPH...65 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNE OR 15 DEGREES AT 24 MPH...39 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...1003 MB...29.62 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Cuban provinces of Isla de la Juventud, La Habana, Ciudad de la
Habana, Matanzas, Cienfuegos, and Villa Clara
* Northwestern Bahamas

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* Craig Key to Golden Beach
* Central Bahamas

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area, in this case within the
next 12-18 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, in this case within 24 hours.

For storm information specific to your area in the United States,
including possible inland watches and warnings, please monitor
products issued by your local National Weather Service forecast
office. For storm information specific to your area outside the
United States, please monitor products issued by your national
meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1100 PM EDT (0300 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Philippe was
located near latitude 24.8 North, longitude 82.1 West. Philippe is
moving toward the north-northeast near 24 mph (39 km/h).  A turn
toward the northeast is expected during the next few hours, and a
rapid motion toward the northeast is expected Sunday through
Monday. On the forecast track, the center of Philippe will move
across the Florida Keys or the southern tip of the Florida peninsula
overnight, and across the northwestern Bahamas Sunday morning.

Maximum sustained winds are near 40 mph (65 km/h) with higher gusts.
Some strengthening is forecast during the next 48 hours.  However,
Philippe is expected to become a post-tropical cyclone on Monday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 105 miles (165 km)
mainly to the east and southeast of the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 1003 mb (29.62 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL: Across the northern Bahamas and south Florida including
the Keys rainfall amounts of 3 to 5 inches with isolated maximum
totals of 8 inches are expected through Sunday.  These rainfall
totals may produce flash flooding, especially in urbanized areas.

Additional rainfall amounts of 1 to 2 inches are possible across
portions of western and central Cuba, which may lead to life-
threatening flash floods and mudslides in the higher terrain.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are likely occurring in the
warning area across Cuba. Tropical storm conditions are expected to
occur in the warning area later tonight across the northwestern
Bahamas.  Tropical storm conditions are possible across the upper
Florida Keys and southeast Florida overnight, and in the central
Bahamas by Sunday morning.

TORNADOES:  An isolated tornado or two is possible across far South
Florida and the Florida Keys tonight.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 200 AM EDT.
Next complete advisory at 500 AM EDT.

$$
Forecaster Beven

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
