<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>EP142017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>6</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170830 09:00:00 PM MDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170831 03:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708310300</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0900 PM MDT Wed Aug 30</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504148400</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>LIDIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>20.7</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-109.2</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>20.7N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>109.2W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>40</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>65</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>35</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>1001</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.56</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNW OR 345 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>7</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>11</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>6</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 160 MI...255 KM SSE OF THE SOUTHERN TIP OF BAJA CALIFORNIA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPEP4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Lidia Advisory Number   6
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       EP142017
900 PM MDT Wed Aug 30 2017

...RAINBANDS ASSOCIATED WITH LIDIA ALREADY REACHING THE SOUTHERN
PORTION OF THE BAJA CALIFORNIA PENINSULA...
...TORRENTIAL RAINS EXPECTED OVER SOUTHWESTERN MEXICO...


SUMMARY OF 900 PM MDT...0300 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...20.7N 109.2W
ABOUT 160 MI...255 KM SSE OF THE SOUTHERN TIP OF BAJA CALIFORNIA
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...40 MPH...65 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNW OR 345 DEGREES AT 7 MPH...11 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...1001 MB...29.56 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* Baja California Sur from Puerto Cortes to east of La Paz

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Baja California Sur from Puerto Cortes to San Evaristo
* mainland Mexico from Bahia Tempehuaya to Huatabampito

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* Baja California Sur from north of San Evaristo to Loreto
* north of Puerto Cortes to Puerto San Andresito

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

Interests elsewhere in western Mexico and Baja California Sur should
monitor the progress of this system.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 900 PM MDT (0300 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Lidia was
located near latitude 20.7 North, longitude 109.2 West. Lidia is
moving toward the north-northwest near 7 mph (11 km/h), and this
motion is expected to continue for the next couple of days. On
the forecast track, the center of Lidia will be near the southern
tip of the Baja California peninsula by late Thursday, and
moving across the peninsula on Friday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 40 mph (65 km/h) with higher gusts.
Some strengthening is forecast during the next 24 hours, and
Lidia still has the opportunity to be near hurricane strength
near the southern portion of the Baja California peninsula.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 115 miles (185 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 1001 mb (29.56 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Lidia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
8 to 12 inches across the Mexican states of Baja California Sur and
western Jalisco, with isolated maximum totals of 20 inches.  In the
Mexican states of Sinaloa, Nayarit, Colima, southern Michoacan,
southern Sonora and central Jalisco, rainfall amounts of 3 to 6
inches are expected. These rains are expected to cause
life-threatening flash floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected to first reach the
coast within the warning area by early Thursday, making outside
preparations difficult or dangerous.  Hurricane conditions are
possible within the hurricane watch area late Thursday.  Tropical
storm conditions are possible in the warning area in mainland Mexico
starting late on Thursday, and in the watch areas in Baja California
Sur on Friday.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge is expected to produce
significant coastal flooding in areas of onshore winds on the
southern portion of Baja California Sur. Near the coast, the
surge will be accompanied by large and destructive waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Lidia are affecting portions of the coast
of southwestern and western Mexico.  These swells will reach the
southern portions of Baja California Sur tonight, and could cause
life-threatening surf and rip current conditions. Please consult
products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 1200 AM MDT.
Next complete advisory at 300 AM MDT.

$$
Forecaster Avila

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
