<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>EP142017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>10</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170831 09:00:00 PM MDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170901 03:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709010300</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0900 PM MDT Thu Aug 31</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504234800</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>LIDIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>23.3</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-110.4</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>23.3N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>110.4W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>65</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>100</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>55</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>991</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.27</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNW OR 335 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>10</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>17</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>9</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 40 MI...70 KM NW OF CABO SAN LUCAS MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPEP4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Lidia Advisory Number  10
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       EP142017
900 PM MDT Thu Aug 31 2017

...LIDIA RESUMES ITS NORTH-NORTHWEST TRACK SPREADING TROPICAL
STORM CONDITIONS OVER SOUTHERN BAJA CALIFORNIA SUR...


SUMMARY OF 900 PM MDT...0300 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...23.3N 110.4W
ABOUT 40 MI...70 KM NW OF CABO SAN LUCAS MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...65 MPH...100 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNW OR 335 DEGREES AT 10 MPH...17 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...991 MB...29.27 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* Baja California Sur from Puerto Cortes to east of La Paz

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Baja California peninsula from Punta Eugenia to Bahia San Juan
Bautista
* Mainland Mexico from Bahia Tempehuaya to Bahia Kino

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* Baja California peninsula north of Punta Eugenia to San Juan De
Las Palomas
* Baja California peninsula north of Bahia San Juan Bautista to
Isla San Luis
* Mainland Mexico north of Bahia Kino to Puerto Libertad

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

Interests elsewhere in western Mexico and the Baja California
peninsula should monitor the progress of Lidia.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 900 PM MDT (0300 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Lidia was
located near latitude 23.3 North, longitude 110.4 West. Lidia is
moving toward the north-northwest near 10 mph (17 km/h), and this
motion is expected to continue through Friday. On the forecast
track, the center of Lidia will move near or over the Baja
California peninsula through Saturday.

Maximum sustained winds remain near 65 mph (100 km/h) with
higher gusts.  A gradual weakening is forecast, but Lidia is
anticipated to remain a tropical storm during the next day or
so.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 185 miles (295 km)
mainly to the north and east of the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 991 mb (29.27 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Lidia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
6 to 12 inches across the Mexican states of Baja California Sur into
Baja California, Sinaloa and the coastal section of Sonora, with
isolated maximum amounts of 20 inches. These rains may cause
life-threatening flash floods and mudslides. Some of the tropical
moisture from Lidia may reach parts of the desert Southwest this
holiday weekend, including southern California, southern Nevada and
southwestern Arizona.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are occurring over the southern
portion of Baja California Sur at this time.  These conditions
should spread northward across the warning area through Friday
night. Hurricane conditions are still possible within the hurricane
watch area during the next few hours.  Tropical storm conditions are
expected in the warning area in mainland Mexico through Friday.
Tropical storm conditions are possible in the watch areas Friday
night or Saturday.  Wind speeds atop and on the windward sides of
hills and mountains are often up to 30 percent stronger than the
near-surface winds indicated in this advisory, and in some elevated
locations could be even greater.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge is expected to produce coastal
flooding in areas of onshore winds on the southern portion of Baja
California Sur.  Near the coast, the surge will be accompanied by
large and destructive waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Lidia are affecting portions of the coast
of southwestern and western Mexico and southern portions of Baja
California Sur, and could cause life-threatening surf and rip
current conditions. Please consult products from your local weather
office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 1200 AM MDT.
Next complete advisory at 300 AM MDT.

$$
Forecaster Avila

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
