<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>EP142017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>16A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170902 12:00:00 PM MDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170902 06:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709021800</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1200 PM MDT Sat Sep 02</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504375200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>LIDIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>28.3</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-114.6</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>28.3N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>114.6W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>40</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>65</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>35</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>999</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.50</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 315 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>12</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>19</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>10</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 40 MI...65 KM NE OF PUNTA EUGENIA MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPEP4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Lidia Intermediate Advisory Number 16A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       EP142017
1200 PM MDT Sat Sep 02 2017

...LIDIA REMAINS A TROPICAL STORM NEAR THE SOUTHERN PART OF THE
STATE OF BAJA CALIFORNIA...


SUMMARY OF 1200 PM MDT...1800 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...28.3N 114.6W
ABOUT 40 MI...65 KM NE OF PUNTA EUGENIA MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...40 MPH...65 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 315 DEGREES AT 12 MPH...19 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...999 MB...29.50 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* The west coast of the Baja California peninsula from Punta
Abreojos to San Jose de Las Palomas
* The east coast of the Baja California peninsula from Mulege to
Isla San Luis
* Mainland Mexico from Guaymas to Puerto Libertad

Interests elsewhere in the Mexican states of Baja California and
Sonora should monitor the progress of Lidia.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1200 PM MDT (1800 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Lidia was
located near latitude 28.3 North, longitude 114.6 West, just
offshore of the southern part of the state of Baja California.
Lidia is moving toward the northwest near 12 mph (19 km/h), and this
motion is expected to continue through Sunday night.  A turn toward
the west-northwest is expected on Monday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 40 mph (65 km/h) with higher
gusts, mainly over the Gulf of California well to the east of the
center. Additional weakening is forecast, and Lidia is expected to
become a tropical depression later today and a remnant low pressure
area tonight or Sunday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 175 miles (280 km)
to the east of the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 999 mb (29.50 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Lidia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
4 to 8 inches across the Mexican states of Baja California Sur into
Baja California and the coastal section of Sonora and northern
Sinaloa, with isolated maximum amounts of 12 inches. These rains may
cause life-threatening flash floods and mudslides. Some of the
tropical moisture from Lidia will spread across parts of the desert
Southwest through this holiday weekend for an increase in scattered
showers and thunderstorms, from southern Nevada and western Arizona
into southern California.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are occurring over portions of the
warning area in the Mexican states of Baja California Sur, Baja
California, and Sonora, especially near the coast of the Gulf of
California.  These conditions should persist for the next few
hours.  Wind speeds atop and on the windward sides of hills and
mountains are often up to 30 percent stronger than the near-surface
winds indicated in this advisory, and in some elevated locations
could be even greater.

STORM SURGE:  Some coastal flooding is possible in areas of onshore
winds along the Baja California peninsula.  Near the coast, the
surge will be accompanied by large waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Lidia are affecting portions of the coast
of western mainland Mexico and the west coast of Baja California
Sur.  These swells could cause life-threatening surf and rip current
conditions.  Please consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 300 PM MDT.

$$
Forecaster Beven

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
