<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>EP142017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>12A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170901 12:00:00 PM MDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170901 06:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709011800</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1200 PM MDT Fri Sep 01</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504288800</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>LIDIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>25.0</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-111.6</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>25.0N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>111.6W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>60</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>95</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>50</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>992</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.29</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 325 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>9</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>15</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>8</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 45 MI...70 KM ENE OF CABO SAN LAZARO MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 100 MI...160 KM NW OF LA PAZ MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPEP4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Lidia Intermediate Advisory Number 12A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       EP142017
1200 PM MDT Fri Sep 01 2017

...CENTER OF LIDIA MOVING NORTHWESTWARD ACROSS SOUTHERN BAJA
CALIFORNIA SUR...
...HEAVY RAINS CONTINUE OVER SOUTHERN BAJA CALIFORNIA SUR AND
PORTIONS OF MAINLAND MEXICO...


SUMMARY OF 1200 PM MDT...1800 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...25.0N 111.6W
ABOUT 45 MI...70 KM ENE OF CABO SAN LAZARO MEXICO
ABOUT 100 MI...160 KM NW OF LA PAZ MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...60 MPH...95 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 325 DEGREES AT 9 MPH...15 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...992 MB...29.29 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Baja California peninsula from San Jose de Las Palomas to Isla
San Luis
* Mainland Mexico from Altata to Puerto Libertad

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

Interests elsewhere in northwestern Mexico and the Baja California
peninsula should monitor the progress of Lidia.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1200 PM MDT (1800 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Lidia was
located over the Mexican state of Baja California Sur near latitude
25.0 North, longitude 111.6 West.  Lidia is moving toward the
northwest near 9 mph (15 km/h) and this motion is expected to
continue with an increase in forward speed during the next couple of
days.  On the forecast track, the center of Lidia will move near or
along the west coast of the Baja California peninsula through
Saturday and then move west of the peninsula over the Pacific Ocean
Saturday night.

Maximum sustained winds are near 60 mph (95 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Weakening is forecast during the next couple of days while
Lidia interacts with the mountainous terrain of the Baja California
peninsula and moves over cold Pacific water.  Lidia is expected to
become a remnant low by Saturday night or Sunday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 195 miles (315 km)
mainly to the east of the center.  Los Mochis recently reported
sustained winds of 45 mph (72 km/h), and a Mexican automated
station near Loreto recently reported sustained winds of 43 mph (69
km/h).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 992 mb (29.29 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Lidia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
6 to 12 inches across the Mexican states of Baja California Sur into
Baja California, Sinaloa and the coastal section of Sonora, with
isolated maximum amounts of 20 inches.  These rains may cause
life-threatening flash floods and mudslides.  Some of the tropical
moisture from Lidia may reach parts of the desert Southwest this
holiday weekend, including southern California, southern Nevada and
southwestern Arizona.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are occurring over the southern
portion of Baja California Sur and over portions of the Mexican
mainland at this time.  These conditions should spread northward
across the warning areas of the Baja California peninsula and
mainland Mexico through Saturday.  Wind speeds atop and on the
windward sides of hills and mountains are often up to 30 percent
stronger than the near-surface winds indicated in this advisory, and
in some elevated locations could be even greater.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge is expected to produce coastal
flooding in areas of onshore winds on the southern portion of Baja
California Sur.  Near the coast, the surge will be accompanied by
large and destructive waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Lidia are affecting portions of the coast
of southwestern and western Mexico and southern portions of Baja
California Sur, and could cause life-threatening surf and rip
current conditions.  Please consult products from your local weather
office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 300 PM MDT.

$$
Forecaster Beven

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
