<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>EP142017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>15A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170902 06:00:00 AM MDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170902 12:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709021200</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0600 AM MDT Sat Sep 02</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504353600</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>LIDIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>27.5</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-114</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>27.5N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>114.0W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>45</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>75</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>40</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>997</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.44</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 320 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>12</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>19</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>10</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 70 MI...115 KM ESE OF PUNTA EUGENIA MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 105 MI...170 KM W OF SANTA ROSALIA MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPEP4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Lidia Intermediate Advisory Number 15A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       EP142017
600 AM MDT Sat Sep 02 2017

...CENTER OF LIDIA MOVING THROUGH NORTHERN BAJA CALIFORNIA SUR...


SUMMARY OF 600 AM MDT...1200 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...27.5N 114.0W
ABOUT 70 MI...115 KM ESE OF PUNTA EUGENIA MEXICO
ABOUT 105 MI...170 KM W OF SANTA ROSALIA MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...45 MPH...75 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 320 DEGREES AT 12 MPH...19 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...997 MB...29.44 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* The west coast of the Baja California peninsula from Puerto San
Andresito to San Jose de Las Palomas
* The east coast of the Baja California peninsula from Loreto to
Isla San Luis
* Mainland Mexico from Guaymas to Puerto Libertad

Interests elsewhere in the Mexican states of Baja California and
Sonora should monitor the progress of Lidia.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 600 AM MDT (1200 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Lidia was
located over Baja California Sur near latitude 27.5 North, longitude
114.0 West.  Lidia is moving toward the northwest near 12 mph
(19 km/h), and this motion is expected to continue through Sunday.
A turn toward the west-northwest is forecast by Sunday night.  On
the forecast track, Lidia's center will move near or along the west
coast of the Baja California peninsula through tonight and then
gradually move away from land on Sunday.

Maximum sustained winds are near 45 mph (75 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Weakening is forecast, and Lidia is expected to become a
tropical depression tonight and then a remnant low on Sunday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 175 miles (280 km)
mainly to the northeast and southeast of the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 997 mb (29.44 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Lidia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
4 to 8 inches across the Mexican states of Baja California Sur into
Baja California and the coastal section of Sonora and northern
Sinaloa, with isolated maximum amounts of 12 inches. These rains may
cause life-threatening flash floods and mudslides. Some of the
tropical moisture from Lidia will spread across parts of the desert
Southwest later this holiday weekend for an increase in scattered
showers and thunderstorms, from southern Nevada and western Arizona
into southern California.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are occurring over portions of the
warning area in the Mexican states of Baja California Sur, Baja
California, and Sonora.  These conditions should spread northward
across the remainder of the warning areas through the day.  Wind
speeds atop and on the windward sides of hills and mountains are
often up to 30 percent stronger than the near-surface winds
indicated in this advisory, and in some elevated locations could be
even greater.

STORM SURGE:  Some coastal flooding is possible in areas of onshore
winds along the Baja California peninsula.  Near the coast, the
surge will be accompanied by large waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Lidia are affecting portions of the coast
of western mainland Mexico and the west coast of Baja California
Sur.  These swells could cause life-threatening surf and rip current
conditions.  Please consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 900 AM MDT.

$$
Forecaster Beven

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
