<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>EP142017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>7</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170831 03:00:00 AM MDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170831 09:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201708310900</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0300 AM MDT Thu Aug 31</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504170000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>LIDIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>21.3</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-109.4</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>21.3N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>109.4W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>45</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>75</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>40</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>997</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.44</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NNW OR 335 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>8</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>13</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>7</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 115 MI...185 KM SSE OF CABO SAN LUCAS MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPEP4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Lidia Advisory Number   7
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       EP142017
300 AM MDT Thu Aug 31 2017

...LIDIA A LITTLE STRONGER...
...CONDITIONS WILL DETERIORATE ACROSS SOUTHERN BAJA CALIFORNIA SUR
THROUGH THE DAY...


SUMMARY OF 300 AM MDT...0900 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...21.3N 109.4W
ABOUT 115 MI...185 KM SSE OF CABO SAN LUCAS MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...45 MPH...75 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NNW OR 335 DEGREES AT 8 MPH...13 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...997 MB...29.44 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of Mexico has extended the Tropical Storm Warning
north of Puerto Cortes to Puerto San Andresito, north of San
Evaristo to Loreto, and north of Huatabampito to Guaymas.  A
Tropical Storm Watch has been issued north of Puerto San Andresito
to Punta Abreojos, north of Loreto to Bahia San Juan Bautista, and
north of Guaymas to Bahia Kino.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* Baja California Sur from Puerto Cortes to east of La Paz

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* Baja California Sur from Puerto San Andresito to Loreto
* mainland Mexico from Bahia Tempehuaya to Guaymas

A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for...
* Baja California Sur north of Puerto San Andresito to Punta
Abreojos
* Baja California Sur north of Loreto to Bahia San Juan Bautista
* mainland Mexico north of Guaymas to Bahia Kino

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area within 36 hours.

A Tropical Storm Watch means that tropical storm conditions are
possible within the watch area, generally within 48 hours.

Interests elsewhere in western Mexico and the Baja California
peninsula should monitor the progress of this system.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 300 AM MDT (0900 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Lidia was
located near latitude 21.3 North, longitude 109.4 West.  Lidia is
moving toward the north-northwest near 8 mph (13 km/h), and this
general motion is expected to continue through midday Friday.  A
turn toward the northwest at a faster forward speed is expected by
Friday night.  On the forecast track, the center of Lidia will be
near the southern tip of the Baja California peninsula this
afternoon, and it will move over the peninsula Friday and Friday
night.

Maximum sustained winds have increased to near 45 mph (75 km/h)
with higher gusts.  Additional strengthening is forecast for the
next 24 hours or so before Lidia's center reaches the Baja
California peninsula.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 160 miles (260 km)
to the east of the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure is 997 mb (29.44 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Lidia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
8 to 12 inches across the Mexican states of Baja California Sur and
western Jalisco, with isolated maximum totals of 20 inches.  In the
Mexican states of Sinaloa, Nayarit, Colima, southern Michoacan,
southern Sonora, and central Jalisco, rainfall amounts of 3 to 6
inches are expected. These rains are expected to cause
life-threatening flash floods and mudslides.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are expected to first reach the
coast within the warning area in Baja California Sur later this
morning, making outside preparations difficult or dangerous.
Hurricane conditions are possible within the hurricane watch area
late today.  Tropical storm conditions are expected in the warning
area in mainland Mexico starting later today or tonight.  Tropical
storm conditions are possible in the watch areas late Friday.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge is expected to produce coastal
flooding in areas of onshore winds on the southern portion of Baja
California Sur.  Near the coast, the surge will be accompanied by
large and destructive waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Lidia are affecting portions of the coast
of southwestern and western Mexico and southern portions of Baja
California Sur, and could cause life-threatening surf and rip
current conditions. Please consult products from your local weather
office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 600 AM MDT.
Next complete advisory at 900 AM MDT.

$$
Forecaster Berg

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
