<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>EP142017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>4</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>17</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170902 02:00:00 PM PDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170902 09:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709022100</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0200 PM PDT Sat Sep 02</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1504386000</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>LIDIA</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>28.8</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-115</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>28.8N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>115.0W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>40</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>65</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>35</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>999</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.50</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 320 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>12</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>19</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>10</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 70 MI...110 KM N OF PUNTA EUGENIA MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPEP4 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Lidia Advisory Number  17
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       EP142017
200 PM PDT Sat Sep 02 2017

...LIDIA CAUSING LIFE-THREATENING RAIN OVER PORTIONS OF BAJA
CALIFORNIA AND MAINLAND MEXICO...


SUMMARY OF 200 PM PDT...2100 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...28.8N 115.0W
ABOUT 70 MI...110 KM N OF PUNTA EUGENIA MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...40 MPH...65 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 320 DEGREES AT 12 MPH...19 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...999 MB...29.50 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The Government of Mexico has discontinued the Tropical Storm
Warning for mainland Mexico, the west coast of the Baja California
peninsula, and the east coast of the Baja California peninsula
south of Bahia San Juan Bautista.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* The east coast of the Baja California peninsula from Bahia San
Juan Bautista to Isla San Luis

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 200 PM PDT (2100 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Lidia was
located near latitude 28.8 North, longitude 115.0 West. Lidia is
moving toward the northwest near 12 mph (19 km/h) and the system is
expected to turn toward the west-northwest at about the same rate
of forward speed during the next two days.

Maximum sustained winds are near 40 mph (65 km/h) with higher gusts.
Some weakening is forecast during the next 48 hours. Lidia is
expected to weaken to a tropical depression tonight and become a
remnant low on Sunday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 175 miles (280 km)
from the center. A Mexican Navy observation site at Isla Cedros
recently recorded a wind gust of 39 mph (63 km/h).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 999 mb (29.50 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Lidia is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
4 to 8 inches across the Mexican states of Baja California Sur into
Baja California and the coastal section of Sonora and northern
Sinaloa, with isolated maximum amounts of 12 inches. These rains may
cause life-threatening flash floods and mudslides. Some of the
tropical moisture from Lidia will spread across parts of the desert
Southwest through this holiday weekend for an increase in scattered
showers and thunderstorms, from southern Nevada and western Arizona
into southern California.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are occurring over portions of the
warning area in the Mexican state of Baja California, along the
coast of the Gulf of California.  These conditions should persist
for the next few hours.  Wind speeds atop and on the windward sides
of hills and mountains are often up to 30 percent stronger than the
near-surface winds indicated in this advisory, and in some elevated
locations could be even greater.

STORM SURGE:  Some coastal flooding is possible in areas of onshore
winds along the Baja California peninsula.  Near the coast, the
surge will be accompanied by large waves.

SURF:  Swells generated by Lidia are affecting portions of the coast
of western mainland Mexico and the west coast of Baja California
Sur.  These swells could cause life-threatening surf and rip current
conditions.  Please consult products from your local weather office.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 500 PM PDT.
Next complete advisory at 800 PM PDT.

$$
Forecaster Landsea

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
