<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>EP162017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>ROUTINE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>1</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>6</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170914 10:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170914 03:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201709141500</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>1000 AM CDT Thu Sep 14</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1505401200</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>HURRICANE</systemType>
<systemName>MAX</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>16.3</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-99.9</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>16.3N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>99.9W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>80</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>130</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>70</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>988</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.18</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>CATEGORY 1</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>E OR 90 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>7</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>11</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>6</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 40 MI...65 KM S OF ACAPULCO MEXICO</systemGeoRefPt1>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPEP1 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Hurricane Max Advisory Number   6
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       EP162017
1000 AM CDT Thu Sep 14 2017

...MAX MOVING EASTWARD JUST SOUTH OF ACAPULCO...
...HEAVY RAINFALL EXPECTED IN THE MEXICAN STATES OF GUERRERO AND
OAXACA...


SUMMARY OF 1000 AM CDT...1500 UTC...INFORMATION
-----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...16.3N 99.9W
ABOUT 40 MI...65 KM S OF ACAPULCO MEXICO
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...80 MPH...130 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...E OR 90 DEGREES AT 7 MPH...11 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...988 MB...29.18 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

The government of Mexico has issued a Tropical Storm Warning and
Hurricane Watch east of Punta Maldonado to Lagunas de Chacahua.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Hurricane Warning is in effect for...
* Zihuatanejo to Punta Maldonado

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* East of Punta Maldonado to Lagunas de Chacahua

A Hurricane Watch is in effect for...
* East of Punta Maldonado to Lagunas de Chacahua

A Hurricane Warning means that hurricane conditions are expected
somewhere within the warning area, in this case within the next 12
hours.  Preparations to protect life and property should be rushed
to completion.

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area, in this case within the
next 12 to 24 hours.

A Hurricane Watch means that hurricane conditions are possible
within the watch area, in this case within the next 12 to 24 hours.

For storm information specific to your area, please monitor
products issued by your national meteorological service.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 1000 AM CDT (1500 UTC), the eye of Hurricane Max was located
near latitude 16.3 North, longitude 99.9 West.  Max is moving toward
the east near 7 mph (11 km/h).  An eastward or east-northeastward
motion at a similar forward speed is expected through Friday.  On
the forecast track, the center of Max is forecast to cross the
coast of southern Mexico in the hurricane warning area this evening
or tonight.

Maximum sustained winds are near 80 mph (130 km/h) with higher
gusts.  Some strengthening is expected today before Max reaches the
coast this evening or tonight.  Weakening is forecast once Max
makes landfall, and it is expected to dissipate over the mountains
of southern Mexico by late Friday.

Hurricane-force winds extend outward up to 10 miles (20 km) from the
center, and tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 45 miles
(75 km).

The estimated minimum central pressure is 988 mb (29.18 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Max is expected to produce total rainfall accumulations
of 5 to 10 inches in the Mexican state of Guerrero and western
portions of the state of Oaxaca. Maximum amounts locally in excess
of 20 inches are possible over coastal areas of Guerrero. These
torrential rains may produce life-threatening flash floods and
mudslides.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are likely occurring within
portions of the hurricane warning area, and hurricane conditions
should begin in that area later today.  Tropical storm conditions
are expected within the tropical storm warning area by this evening,
with hurricane conditions possible tonight.

STORM SURGE:  A dangerous storm surge is expected to produce
significant coastal flooding near and to the east of where the
center makes landfall.  Near the coast, the surge will be
accompanied by large and destructive waves.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next intermediate advisory at 100 PM CDT.
Next complete advisory at 400 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Berg

NNNN
</message>
</cycloneMessage>
